<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The treasury of drugs unlock'd, or, A full and true description of all sorts of drugs and chymical preparations sold by druggists whereby you may know the place of their growth and how to distinguish the good from the bad : very useful for all gentlemen, merchants, druggists, doctors, apothecaries, chirurgeons, and their apprentices ... the whole work alphabetically digested with a compleat catalogue of all drugs, &amp;c. / by Jo. Jacob Berlu ...</title>
            <author>Berlu, Jo. Jacob (John Jacob)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 168 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 103 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A27470</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B1980</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36588</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15735475</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15735475</idno>
            <idno type="VID">104566</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A27470)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104566)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1165:1)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The treasury of drugs unlock'd, or, A full and true description of all sorts of drugs and chymical preparations sold by druggists whereby you may know the place of their growth and how to distinguish the good from the bad : very useful for all gentlemen, merchants, druggists, doctors, apothecaries, chirurgeons, and their apprentices ... the whole work alphabetically digested with a compleat catalogue of all drugs, &amp;c. / by Jo. Jacob Berlu ...</title>
                  <author>Berlu, Jo. Jacob (John Jacob)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[5], 125 [i.e. 147], [15] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Harris ... and Tho. Howkins ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Price bound one shilling."</note>
                  <note>Advertisements: p. [14]-[15] at end.</note>
                  <note>Error in paging: p. 117-125 repeated in numbering.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages torn and creased; t.p. and p. 30-65 from defective Cambridge University Library copy spliced at end.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Pharmacopoeias --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="note">
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:1"/>
            <head>ADVERTISEMENT.
<figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <p>FOR the better finding out what Drugs are Prohibited, they are marked thus *, being not brought directly from the Place of growth in Engliſh built Shipping, as in the New Book of Rates, <hi>p.</hi> 112 in the Act for Incouraging and Increaſing of Ship<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping and Navigation, is more largely expreſſed. You will find thoſe that are Prohibited with this mark *, both in the Book and Catalogue.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE TREASURY OF <hi>DRVGS</hi> UNLOCK'D.</p>
            <p>OR A Full and True Deſcription of all ſorts of <hi>Drugs,</hi> and Chymical Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parations, ſold by <hi>Drugiſts,</hi> Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by you may know the place of their growth, and from whence they come, and how to diſtinguiſh the Good from the Bad.</p>
            <p>Very USEFUL for All Gentlemen, Merchants, Druggiſts, Doctors, Apothecaries, Chirurgeons, and their Apprentices. As alſo for all Travellers, Seamen, Cuſtomhouſe Officers, and all others that either Traffick in them, or make any uſe of them, or thoſe that Import or deliver any of 'em at the Waterſide. Giving a true Accou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> of all thoſe that are Prohibited, and thoſe tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, whereby many needleſs Diſputes and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Suits may be prevented. The whole Work Alphabetically digeſted, with a compleat Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>talogue of all Drugs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>By Jo. Jacob Berl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of <hi>London,</hi> Merchant in Drugs.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>John Harris</hi> at the <hi>Harrow</hi> againſt the Church in the <hi>Poultrey,</hi> and <hi>Tho<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Howkins</hi> in <hi>George-Yard,</hi> in <hi>Lombard-ſtret,</hi> 16<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>Price Bound One Shilling.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:2"/>
            <head>Courteous and Benevolent READER.</head>
            <p>CErtainly nothing can promote Trade more than for Men to learn and underſtand thoſe Commodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties and Merchandizes; they do intend to Trade in; which gives me hopes that this Treatiſe will be kindly accepted of, and that thoſe of the Trade of Druggiſt will be more Ingenuous than to hold that <hi>Popiſh</hi> Tenet, to keep the People in Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance. The Price Currant which is weekly publiſhed of Drugs, may pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice, this cannot: For the more Men underſtand the goodneſs of a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modity, the more value they will ſet up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on it.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:3"/>
            <p> To avoid alſo thoſe dangers (of pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibited Goods) by which I have been (as it were) ſhipwracked, you will eaſily diſcern the places of growth, being menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned almoſt to every Commodity, and thereby avoid thoſe Rocks and Perils by which I have fore-gone a good eſtate. <hi>Vale.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:104566:3"/>
            <head>THE TREASURY OF <hi>DRVGS</hi> UNLOCK'D.</head>
            <div n="a" type="part">
               <head>A.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Adianthum Album, Adianthum Nigrum, Maidenhair.</head>
                  <p>THe black groweth here in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, France, Germany,</hi> and <hi>Norway,</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi> It is to be choſen, the Leaves very green, the ſtalks of a lively reddiſh, black and dry withal. There has of late been a very good ſort brought from <hi>Bergen</hi> in <hi>Norway;</hi> that
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:104566:4"/> which comes from <hi>Briſtol,</hi> and other parts in <hi>Wales,</hi> is generally very good alſo.</p>
                  <p>The white <hi>Maiden Hair</hi> is not ſo plenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful here, neither ſo much in uſe. It is brought from <hi>Italy, New-England, France,</hi> and other places; the Stalk of it is more of yellowiſh green, and the Leaves larger and thinner than the black.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Adeps Caſtoris.</head>
                  <p>THe Fat of <hi>Caſtor</hi> is taken from above the Cods of <hi>Caſtor,</hi> of which the <hi>Dantzick</hi> and <hi>Poland</hi> ſort generally have, as it were, two Cods above the <hi>Caſtor</hi> Cods, which are full of Fat.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Adeps Hominis.</head>
                  <p>THE Fat of Man is gathered from thoſe parts of Men, as Suet is made of other Creatures, and Hogs Lard from Hogs, of which the ſweeteſt and cleaneſt is to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Adeps Urſi.</head>
                  <p>THE Fat of a Bear is of a very ſtinking ſtrong ſmell, very greaſie; 'tis for the moſt part brought from <hi>Greenland</hi>
                     <pb n="3" facs="tcp:104566:4"/> and other parts out of the North Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Alumen Commune.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>COmmon Allum</hi> is made here in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and a great many other parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> it is in large great Lumps of a ſowriſh aſtringent taſte, white, and clear.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Alumen Plumoſum.</head>
                  <p>IS in long ſhivers and long flakes, covered over with a ſmall white fine Duſt, not unlike to Feathers; it comes from <hi>Chio</hi> in the <hi>Straits,</hi> and likewiſe out of ſome parts of <hi>Germany:</hi> the beſt is in long flakes above an inch in length.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Alumen Roch.</head>
                  <p>IS an <hi>Allum</hi> which is roched, looks red<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſh and very clear as a Cryſtal, if broken, and tranſparent; it comes from <hi>Smyrna</hi> in <hi>Turky,</hi> and ſome places in <hi>Italy.</hi> It is alſo called <hi>Roman Allum.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="4" facs="tcp:104566:5"/>
                  <head>Agaricus.</head>
                  <p>'TIS an Excreſcence of a fungous Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of a Tree, very white, and light, and cuts eaſily and ſhort: the beſt comes from <hi>Barbary;</hi> there is another ſort which comes from <hi>Helvetia,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Germany,</hi> viz. <hi>Norimberg;</hi> which is finer than that which comes from <hi>Ruſſia,</hi> being in ſmall pieces, but very fine, white, and light: the <hi>Ruſſia</hi> ſort is the courſeſt of all, being ſometimes very cruſty, and interwoven with red Veins, as alſo flinty and ſandy, which is reckoned the worſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Alce Succotrina.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the fineſt of <hi>Aloes,</hi> therefore by ſome called <hi>Aloe Lucida;</hi> 'tis made in an Iſland called <hi>Succatora</hi> near <hi>Moco</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt Indies;</hi> the fineſt is moſt tranſparent, if broken, it turns to a fine yellowiſh Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der: 'tis brought to us from the <hi>Eaſt-In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies:</hi> the ſmalleſt, thinneſt, and lighteſt Bladders are to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="5" facs="tcp:104566:5"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Aloe Hepatica.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THE right <hi>Aloe Hepatica</hi> ought to be of a fine light Liver colour, fine and clear, not very foetid in ſmell; that which is called ſo he<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e in <hi>England</hi> is nothing elſe but <hi>Aloe Caballina,</hi> of a ſtrong foetid ſmell, and very courſe, fitter to be given to Horſes than Men: it comes from <hi>Surrat</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Aloe Barbados.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the ſame as the former, but rather finer, yet of a foetid ſmell; it comes in gourds, which is generally the beſt: ſome in pots is pretty good; that which comes in Casks is moiſt, and inferiour to the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Ambra Griſea.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>AMbergreeſe,</hi> the beſt is of an Ash co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, ſomething ſpeckled, with lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle ſmall black and white ſpecks; it is of a moſt fragrant, pleaſant ſmell, clear from any droſs, and not cruſty without, run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning a hot Needle ſlightly into it, there will iſſue out a Fatneſs of a fragrant ſcent;
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:104566:6"/>
'tis brought from the <hi>Eaſt</hi> and <hi>Weſt Indies</hi> (viz. <hi>Bermoodos,</hi> &amp;c.) and ſometimes 'tis found in near parts adjacent: There was lately a piece diſcovered in a <hi>Sperma Ceti Whale</hi> in <hi>Ireland,</hi> ſomewhat like <hi>Ambergreeſe</hi> 'tis never the worſe if it does incline to a yellowiſh colour; ſometimes you will diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover the beaks of Birds in it, which is a ſymptome of its trueneſs: it has been ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerved that Birds will generally ſtrike at it, and ſeveral pieces floating at Sea have by that means been taken up.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Ambra Nigra.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>BLack Ambergreeſe,</hi> the beſt cometh from the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> being of a black colour, ſometimes ſpeckled with a few grey Specks: We have had in former times an <hi>Iriſh</hi> black <hi>Ambergreeſe,</hi> which was more foetid than fragrant, breaking ſoftiſh and very ſhining, but of late (tho' much en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired for) ſcarce to be had for Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Amber Liquid.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a very fine and fragrant Liquor of the ſame Condenſity, as a <hi>Straſbourg Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentine,</hi> of a pale reddiſh colour; it comes
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:104566:6"/> from <hi>Aegypt, Chio,</hi> and the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Amygdala Amara.</head>
                  <p>BItter <hi>Almonds</hi> are to be choſen freſh, large, breaking white within, of a bright colour without, they come moſt generally from <hi>Barbary,</hi> ſome few from <hi>Province,</hi> and other parts of <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Amygdala Dulcis.</head>
                  <p>SWeet <hi>Almonds</hi> are to be choſen as aforeſaid, but of a ſweet taſte, without rancor, the beſt are the <hi>Jordan,</hi> after them <hi>Province</hi> and <hi>Barbary Almonds.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Anacardia</head>
                  <p>IS the Fruit of an <hi>Indian</hi> Tree, like a Birds Heart, with Juice like Blood; it is by ſome called the <hi>Elephants Lowſe;</hi> it is brought from <hi>Bantam</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Antimonium Crudum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CRude Antimony</hi> is a Mineral Body, in which the <hi>Metalline</hi> nature is finiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, conſiſting of Sulphur Mineral, of
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:104566:7"/> Metallic Mercury indigeſted, and of an earthly Subſtance intermixt with Salt: That which is brought to us comes from <hi>Dantzick</hi> and <hi>Poland,</hi> which is in Loaves of a pretty length being larger ſtreak'd, and leſs foot in it than that which comes from <hi>France,</hi> which is in large, round, thick Loaves, full of foot, and nothing nigh ſo good as the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Antimonium Hungar.</head>
                  <p>OF all <hi>Antimonies,</hi> the <hi>Hungarian</hi> and <hi>Tranſylvanian Antimony</hi> is to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred, becauſe that it is of a purer Sul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phur, and inbibeth a Golden Mineral; therefore are its ſtreaks more ſplendid and longer, of an obſcure reddiſhneſs, which ſhoweth its goodneſs; 'tis caſt in a Pyramid faſhioned Loaf, and this <hi>Antimo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny</hi> is in all Medicines to be preferr'd be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore any other.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Antimonium Diaph.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>DIaphoretick Antimony</hi> is a Chymical Preparation, with <hi>Nitre</hi> and <hi>Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony,</hi> and Waſhing, that it comes very white and light.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="9" facs="tcp:104566:7"/>
                  <head>Antimonii Vitrum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>OR Stibium,</hi> is a Glaſs of <hi>Antimony,</hi> looks a tranſparent deep red, Chymical<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſo prepared, and that moſt in <hi>Amſter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Antimonii Ceruſſa</head>
                  <p>IS Chymically prepared from <hi>Antimo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny,</hi> &amp;c. made here in Town, being very white.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Aqua Fortis.</head>
                  <p>OF <hi>Aqua Fortis</hi> there is in <hi>Druggiſts Shops</hi> ſold, <hi>viz.</hi> double and ſingle. It is a Chymical Preparation, drawn from <hi>Salt petre</hi> and <hi>Copperas,</hi> to ſeveral degrees; the ſtrength of it is known by pouring it upon the blade of a Knife, by its ſtrong ſcent, fum<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>g and eating in preſently in the blade of a Knife, or any thing of Braſs or Co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>er, as alſo by the quickly rotting a Pack-thred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="10" facs="tcp:104566:8"/>
                  <head>Aqua flor. Aurant.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ORange Flower Water</hi> is brought to us from <hi>Province</hi> and <hi>Nizza,</hi> in <hi>France,</hi> as alſo from <hi>Genoua</hi> and other parts of <hi>Ita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly.</hi> Its Goodneſs is only known by the rare odoriferous and fragrant Smell by dipping your Handkerchief, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Argentum Vivum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>QUick Silver</hi> is a Mineral Liquor, or a Metallic Volatile; the beſt is <hi>Virgin Quick Silver,</hi> or that which is ſometimes naturally found in the Earth, tho' moſt of it is made of a Mineral which is called <hi>Cinnaber,</hi> by the force of Fire, as alſo drawn out of other Metals; 'tis found in quanti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in <hi>Hungaria, Tranſylvania, Tyrol,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Germany,</hi> and ſome parts of <hi>Spain.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Aroma Equinum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>HOrſe Spice</hi> is a thing made here in <hi>England</hi> of ſeveral Ingredients, as <hi>Foenugrick, Turmerick, Long Pepper,</hi> &amp;c. All ground together in Powder.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="11" facs="tcp:104566:8"/>
                  <head>Auriculae Judae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JEws Ears</hi> is a ſpungy Excreſcency out of Elder Trees, they are found here in <hi>England</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Auripigmentum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ORpment</hi> is a ſecundary Sulphureou Mineral, but inflammable: the fineſt comes from <hi>Surrat</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of a ſhining Gold colour, there is a great deal in <hi>Saxony</hi> in <hi>Germany,</hi> but courſer and lighter yellow, inclining to a green, more hard and rocky than the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Aerugo Aeris.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>VErdigreaſe</hi> is a thing made out of Copper, which by the Evapora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting of new Wine turns to a green Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, and ſo gathered in Leather Bags, and brought to us from <hi>Marſeilles</hi> in <hi>France;</hi> that which is of a dry and lively colour, breaking eaſily into Powder, is to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferr'd.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="12" facs="tcp:104566:9"/>
                  <head>Aes Uſtum.</head>
                  <p>IS nothing elſe but the Scales of Copper Calcined in a Reverberatory Fire; which are eaſily reduced into a Calx by beating them in a Mortar.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Arſenicum Album.</head>
                  <p>VVHite <hi>Rats-bane,</hi> the beſt of it breaks clear and tranſparent like Cryſtal, and comes out of <hi>Saxony,</hi> by way of <hi>Hamborough;</hi> it's nothing elſe but a fuſion of <hi>Orpment</hi> and <hi>Salt,</hi> and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore not a natural but an artificial thing.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Arſenicum Citrinum.</head>
                  <p>YEllow <hi>Arſenick</hi> comes likewiſe out of <hi>Saxony;</hi> It is to be choſen of a pure yellow colour, breaking clear within.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Arſenicum Rubrum.</head>
                  <p>BY ſome called <hi>Roſe Alger,</hi> alias <hi>Arſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nic Sandarac,</hi> is of an <hi>Orange</hi> colour, if beaten to Powder, the moſt pernicious of Poyſons; even outwardly applied, it pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duceth
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:104566:9"/> horrible Effects, this comes from the places aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="b" type="part">
               <head>B</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Baccae Alkekengi, Winter Cherries.</head>
                  <p>THey grow here againſt a Wall in <hi>England,</hi> and in a great many other parts wild amongſt the Vineyards. The Berries are in a husk reſembling red Cher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, but a little more of an <hi>Orange</hi> co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, being well dried, they will conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nue of a lively red colour, a little en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clining to yellow.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Baccae Coffee.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>COho Seeds,</hi> or <hi>Coffee,</hi> is a Berry which groweth upon a Shrub in the Deſarts of <hi>Arabia Foelix,</hi> f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>om whence it is carried through all the <hi>Grand Siegnior</hi>'s Dominions even to the <hi>Eaſt Indies;</hi> the beſt comes now from the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing large, bright, a full <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>erry, and clean. Formerly that which came from <hi>Turky;</hi> (which generally looks a little greeniſh) was
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:104566:10"/> beſt eſteemed; great quantities are yearly imported from both parts.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Baccae Hederae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>IVY Berries</hi> grow in <hi>England</hi> and all parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> they are to be choſen of a good full growth and well dried, and ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thered in the right ſeaſon.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Baccae Juniperi.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JUniper Berries</hi> grow here and in all parts of <hi>Europe:</hi> the largeſt and freſheſt of a good pleaſant Smell, black without, and very green within, are to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Baccae Lauri.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LAurberries, Bay Berries</hi> is a large Berry brought to us from <hi>Port a Port,</hi> of a very hot oleaginous taſte, a little inclining to black, brown Kernels within, they come from ſeveral parts of the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Baccae Myrti.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MYrtilberries</hi> grow in <hi>Italy, France,</hi> and other hot Countries near the Rocks and Cliffs of the Sea, brought to us from <hi>Marſeilles.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="15" facs="tcp:104566:10"/>
                  <head>Baccae Kermes.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALkermes Berries</hi> is of a lively red co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, very light, and ſoon broken, ſomething like a Fly within. They come from <hi>Italy, Venice, France,</hi> and <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeilles.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Balſamum Capivi.</head>
                  <p>IS a Natural <hi>Balſam</hi> flowing from a <hi>Bal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſam</hi> Tree in <hi>Surinam</hi> in the <hi>Weſt Indies,</hi> of an Aromatic Smell, hot and bitter taſte, of a body clear, tranſparent, like <hi>Venice Turpentine,</hi> but exceeding all <hi>Turpentine</hi> for Goodneſs and Vertue.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Balſamum Judaicum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>BAlm of Gilead,</hi> by ſome called of <hi>Mec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cha,</hi> by other <hi>Balſamum Syriacum,</hi> is a Balſam much reſembling the former, but of a more condens'd Body; if ſome drops are poured into Water, it will ſpread upon the ſurface of the Water, and uphold a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle piece of Tobacco Pipe; it is very fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant, of Smell ſomewhat like Roſemary and Sage Flowers: 'tis brought to us from <hi>Turky,</hi> and is ſaid to grow out of a thorny Tree in <hi>Arabia, Media</hi> and <hi>India.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="16" facs="tcp:104566:11"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Balſamum Peruanum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>NAtural Balſam, Indian Balſam</hi> is of a a very fragrant ſweet Smell, a red<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſh black colour, ſinking under Water; 'tis brought to us from <hi>Peru,</hi> and <hi>New Spain,</hi> in earthen Jars covered over with Leather.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Balſamum Sulphuris,</head>
                  <p>IS nothing elſe but a Chymical Prepara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion made out of Flower of Brimſtone, and Oyl of <hi>Turpentine,</hi> till it comes to a moſt curious Balſamic condenſity, red like a Ruby, ſometimes 'tis made with Oyl of ſweet Fennel, or Annis-ſeed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Balſamum Tolutanum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>BAlſam Tolu,</hi> is a Balſamous Liquor, of a red, inclining to a Gold colour, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſting between a liquid and a thick Body, very glutinous, where ever it faſtneth it ſticks cloſe to it, and pleaſant in Smell (and not nauſeous like other Balſams) like the beſt of Lemons, and Jaſmin Flowers; 'tis brought from <hi>Carthagena,</hi> by the Natives called <hi>Tolu,</hi> out of the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt Indies,</hi> in large and ſmall Callabaſtes.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="17" facs="tcp:104566:11"/>
                  <head>Bolus Armenus.</head>
                  <p>FIne Bole or <hi>Bolus verus,</hi> it taketh its name from <hi>Armenia,</hi> a Country be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yond <hi>Greece,</hi> and is often brought from <hi>Turky</hi> and the <hi>Straits;</hi> 'tis alſo digged in <hi>Germany,</hi> nea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>Wirtemberg,</hi> and great ſtore, its ſaid, may be had in St. <hi>Helena;</hi> the fineſt is of a fattiſh red colour, being put to the tongue will eaſily ſtick faſt to it, being put in the water will as eaſily diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolve, as Butter in melting.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Bolus Communis.</head>
                  <p>Common Bole is a thing made here in <hi>England</hi> of Red-oaker and White<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the nearer it comes to the fine, the better eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Borax.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a thing made out of natural Borax or Tincal, being in a manner refined from its Droſs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> is in pretty large Lumps, bigger than a Walnut, white, almoſt tranſparent, of taſte not acid, but as it were urinous. It is refin'd here, and in <hi>Holland,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="18" facs="tcp:104566:12"/>
                  <head>Butyrum Jeſſamin.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JEſſamin</hi> Butter is made out of the <hi>Jeſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min</hi> Flowers and Lard, finely beaten in a Marble Mortar.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Bang.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS an Herb which comes from <hi>Bantam</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> of an Infatuating quali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and pernicious uſe.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="c" type="part">
               <head>C.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Camphora.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CAmphora</hi> or <hi>Camphor</hi> is a Gum of a Tree, of which there is great plenty in <hi>Japan,</hi> in <hi>Burneo</hi> and <hi>China,</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> from whence it is brought to us in Duppers and Casks un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>refined, being refined in large round Casks, is of a clear and almoſt traſparent body, of a white Cryſtalline colour, and Odoriferous ſtrong ſmell, like the beſt Oyl of <hi>Spike,</hi> of a Volatile quality, eaſily diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolving,
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:104566:12"/> being ſet on fire almoſt inex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinguible, burning in Water and Air; and therefore of great uſe in Bombs, Carcaſſes, and other Fire-Works.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cantharides.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CAntharides,</hi> or <hi>Spaniſh Flies,</hi> is an Inſect which groweth out of <hi>Aſh-Tree-leaves;</hi> they are found in Meadows and Corn-fields; they are to be choſen of a very lively green Colour, freſh, whole and large, without Duſt, of a longiſh body. They come from <hi>France, Spain, Italy</hi> and <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cap. Papaver. Albi.</head>
                  <p>WHite <hi>Poppy head</hi> grows here in moſt parts of <hi>England, Germany, France,</hi> &amp;c. being of very large Heads; a white <hi>Poppy ſeed</hi> within: Sometimes the Seeds are brought out of <hi>France,</hi> being very white and of a ſweet taſte, cauſing ſleepineſs.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Carabe.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>AMber,</hi> or <hi>Succinum,</hi> is a bituminous Subſtance; or as ſome ſay, <hi>a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſin of the Earth,</hi> and out of old Trees
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:104566:13"/> thorowly digeſted; and from thence traduced into the Seas. The beſt is reckoned the White, which is ſaid to be the fatteſt; the yellow or clear Amber colour the next to it; ſome of three or four pounds a piece in weight. They make ſeveral Toyes of it, as Necklaces, Knife hafts, Cabinets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and a great deal is carried to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies;</hi> the brown and black is the worſt, only fit to draw Oyl and Salt; it is found near the Sea-ſhores of <hi>Pruſſia,</hi> and brought to Sale at <hi>Coningsberg.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cariophylli.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>CLoves, or little Cloves, ſo called, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe 'tis ſaid they are beaten down before their full growth; thoſe are to be choſen which are black, oyly, very hot in the taſt, of a ſtrong odoriferous ſmell. There is another ſort which is called <hi>Antophylli,</hi> or Mother Cloves, which are large, full grown, but not ſo good as the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Carpobalſamum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>SHould be the Berry that comes from the ſame Tree, out of which <hi>Balm</hi>
                     <pb n="21" facs="tcp:104566:13"/> of <hi>Gilead</hi> is made, of a longiſh ſhape; ſomewhat like to <hi>Cubebs</hi> in the taſte; growing formerly in <hi>Paleſtina,</hi> then in <hi>Syria,</hi> but now tranſplanted into <hi>Egypt:</hi> but here in <hi>England</hi> we uſe the <hi>Jamaica</hi> Pepper, or <hi>Pimento,</hi> of which the ſmal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſt, roundeſt, and of a fragrant ſmell, (like Cloves) is to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Caſſia Fiſtularis.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the fruit of a Tree growing in long Canes, or Pipes, hanging very full and thick on the Branches: The beſt of all cometh from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and great quantities uſed to be brought from <hi>Bantam;</hi> it is of a thin rind, full of Pulp, and free from ratling: There are alſo quantities brought from the <hi>Weſt-Indies,</hi> as St. <hi>Martenico, Gardelup, Braſſil,</hi> &amp;c. of which ſort the Pipes are gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally large and thick rinded, and not ſo pulpy within, and therefore worth a great deal leſs than the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> ſort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Caſtoreum Angl. Nov.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>NEw-England</hi> Caſtor is the worſt of all Caſtors, being in longiſh, hard, and thin Cods, the ſubſtance within
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:104566:14"/> more like Reſin than Caſtor; they are the Cods from a Beaver: There is a ſort which has been lately brought from <hi>Hudſon</hi>'s Bay, which is in ſhape of the Cods ſomething like <hi>New-England,</hi> but in Quality and goodneſs far exceeding it, being moiſter in the Cods, and the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner ſubſtance of a very ſtrong ſmell and taſte, little inferiour to the <hi>Poland</hi> ſort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Castoreum Ruſſiae.</head>
                  <p>IS the Cods or Stones of a Beaver; The beſt of all <hi>Ruſſia,</hi> or other Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtor, is that of <hi>Siberia,</hi> of a ſtrong and grave ſmell, of good large round Cods well fed, neither too dry nor too moiſt, if cut of a red liver colour. There is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother ſort which is brought from <hi>Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> and <hi>Dantzick,</hi> which is generally fat and moiſt, and nothing near ſo good as the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cera Alba.</head>
                  <p>WHite Wax is made out of yellow Wax, the ſame being by a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Engine turned into ſmall Flakes and Shivers, and bleached in the Sun, will turn white as Snow; which afterwards
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:104566:14"/> is caſt into round Cakes, ſome thicker, others thinner, that is to be choſen, which ſmells well and chaws hard, not being mixt with Sheeps or Lambs Suet, and and that which looketh very white with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the leaſt caſt of any yellowneſs.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cera Flava.</head>
                  <p>YEllow wax is made here in <hi>England</hi> from the Bee-hives, of a firm bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, and pleaſant ſmell, it is of a good lively Colour, and made up in round Cakes of ſeveral bigneſs: That which comes from <hi>Dantzick</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Eaſt</hi> Country, is likewiſe very good, and free from Adulteration. That which comes from <hi>Guinea</hi> and <hi>African</hi> parts, is nothing near ſo good, being caſt in Sand and adulterated, and of no good Colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Ceterach.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CEterach</hi> is an Herb which comes out of <hi>Germany;</hi> 'tis of a very <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ender ſubſtance, of a light browniſh Colour, eaſily running to duſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="24" facs="tcp:104566:15"/>
                  <head>Chamaepitys.</head>
                  <p>GRound Pine, <hi>alias, Iva arthetica,</hi> is a Herb which is in ſandy ground here in <hi>England,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> having a blewiſh Flower.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Chalybs Crud.</head>
                  <p>STeel is nothing elſe but Iron in the beſt way purged; that which comes from <hi>Styria</hi> and <hi>Venice,</hi> is generally reputed the beſt: Other ſorts come from <hi>Cologne</hi> and <hi>Bergſland;</hi> but inferi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our to the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Chalybs Preparat.</head>
                  <p>IS Steel Chymically prepared by a ſtrong Acid, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Ceruſſa Veneta.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CEruſſa,</hi> or fine white Lead of <hi>Venice,</hi> is in little fine Loaves, wrapped up in blew Papers, brought over to us be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing very heavy; formerly it uſed to be brought from <hi>Venice,</hi> now great ſtore is imported from <hi>Holland;</hi> but that
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:104566:15"/> which is made here in <hi>England,</hi> is better eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cinnabaris Factitia.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>VErmilion,</hi> or made <hi>Cinnaber,</hi> is of a very fine lively red colour, made out of Quick-Silver and Brimſtone by the Chymical Art. Firſt, it was made only in <hi>Italy;</hi> afterward great quantities were imported from <hi>Holland;</hi> and now it is likewiſe made in <hi>England:</hi> The goodneſs is known by its pure fine red colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cinnabaris Nativa.</head>
                  <p>NAtural <hi>Cinnaber</hi> is a Mineral conſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Sulphur and live Mercury; ſome doth reſemble a red Stone; the fineſt is a very ſmooth drop of a pure red, gliſtering and ſhining like the beſt of Vermilion; it is ſaid to be found in <hi>Lybia;</hi> but of late, the <hi>Dutch</hi> have brought the fineſt yet ſeen from <hi>Japan,</hi> out of the <hi>Eaſt-Indies:</hi> That which is found in <hi>Germany,</hi> is rocky and ſtony, and far inferiour to the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:104566:16"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Cochinille.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a fine little Berry, breaking in a very dark red Powder, grayiſh co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loured without; in ſhape like that In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſect, called <hi>Lady-bird,</hi> but ſomething leſs, and therefore by many believed to be a Flie, (or an Inſect) which cannot be, that any ſuch rich colour can be in any ſuch Creature: The trueſt account I ever could learn, is, that ſome Flies and Inſects faſtening upon the leaves (which are ſharp as Needles) of a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Shrub, on which your <hi>Weſt-India</hi> Shoak-bears do grow, cauſes a kind of a bliſter, turning very red at firſt, and grayiſh the outſide. After the <hi>Indians</hi> do rub all the other part of the leaf when dry, and thus the <hi>Cochinille</hi> is produced: Others think it only the bloſſom of a tender Herb, taken off before it flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers; 'tis of an excellent colour, of which all the fineſt Scarlet and Purple are dyed. Brought from <hi>New Spain</hi> and <hi>Mexico.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Corallina.</head>
                  <p>IS nothing elſe but a Sea-moſs, <hi>(Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cus Marinus)</hi> growing in little white
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:104566:16"/> threads, as ſmall Vipers to the Rock, like the Moſs to a Tree, being good, is very white in longiſh Strings, like the unrifling of a courſe white Linnen; ſome of an inch long, ſome ſhorter, 'tis of a ſaltiſh taſte, the ſmell reſembling to Oiſters.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Corallium Album.</head>
                  <p>WHite Coral is ſaid to be a ſtony Juice growing under water in the Sea; ſome like the ſmall branches of a Tree, others of ſeveral forms and ſhapes, (I have ſeen pieces of half a hundred Weight, covering pieces of the Wrack where the Silver was fetcht out) the beſt of it is that which is pure, white and clear, almoſt tranſparent; free from Droſs, reſembling almoſt the white Wax: It comes generally from the <hi>Weſt-Indies,</hi> and other parts near <hi>Spain</hi> and <hi>France;</hi> there is a courſe ſort like to pieces of Tobacco-Pipes, ſome ſmall like Sugar-Confects, is better; but the beſt, is of good handſome clear Branches, and very clear and white.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="28" facs="tcp:104566:17"/>
                  <head>Corallium Rubrum.</head>
                  <p>REd Coral, of a moſt pure red co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, like Vermillion when polliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and in large Branches, ſuch as uſed to be tranſported to the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> is beſt. But for Phyſical uſes, a ſmall little Sprig ſort is uſed likewiſe; that of a pure red is to be preferred; the pale ſcruffy ſort is nothing near ſo good: It is brought from the <hi>Tyrrhene</hi> and <hi>Sioilian</hi> Seas, as likewiſe, ſome parts of <hi>Italy,</hi> and is poliſhed at <hi>Naples.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cornu Alcis.</head>
                  <p>THe Horn of an <hi>Elck</hi> is of ſeveral ſhapes, but that which is beſt for uſe, is a broad, ſlat, thick, heavy Horn, a little hollowiſh at one ſide; if white within, fit for raſping; is in ſome caſes to be preferred before Harts-horn.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cornu Cervi.</head>
                  <p>HArts-horn, or Stags horn, of which the beſt come out of <hi>Germany;</hi> the large with white and clear tips, of a good freſh colour without, and very
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:104566:17"/> white within, are beſt; thoſe which come from the Eaſt-Countreys, <hi>Scotland</hi> and <hi>Norway,</hi> are not ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cornu Rhinocerotis.</head>
                  <p>THe <hi>Rhinoceros</hi> horn is of a dark browniſh colour, with a ſharp point, moſtly bendeth Half-Moon fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhion, but the Root very broad and heavy: I have ſeen ſome of three foot in length; they are brought over from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cornu Unicornu.</head>
                  <p>THe <hi>Unicorns</hi> horn is ſometimes eight foot and more in length, others of a ſmaller ſize; they are very ſharp pointed, running taper all along, and twiſted of the colour of Ivory, and a finer grain than any Ivory, and very white within, they are not of a four leg'd Creature, like to a Horſe, but come from a Fiſh, and therefore a Sea-Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corn; they are brought from the <hi>Straits Davids,</hi> near the North-Paſſage.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="30" facs="tcp:104566:18"/>
                  <head>Cortex Cappari Rad.</head>
                  <p>CAper-bark is of the Roots of a Caper Tree, or rather a Shrub, whereupon the Capers grow; the Bark is beſt which is bright, a fair Paiſnip colour, and ſomewhat large, and not Worm eaten.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cortex Caſſiae Ligneae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CAſſia-Lignea</hi> is of ſeveral ſorts, the moſt and beſt for Phyſical Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription, is the quill ſort, (being made up in ſmall bundles) the thickneſs of a Gooſe Quill, generally ſixteen Inches, or thereabouts, long, of a bright light Cin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>namen colour, of a ſweet, but not ſharp biting, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of a glutenous taſt when chawed. There is another ſort, which is called the <hi>Tramboon</hi> ſort, of which there is one kind in bundles like Clove-Park, of a very hot biting taſt, break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing gummy as it were, and blackiſh wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thin like Clove-Bark, which is very good alſo; then likewiſe another ſort much like this laſt, in large thick rowles as big as a Thigh, which proves pretty good and ſtrong, but is of a very dark
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:104566:18"/> colour. Others of the <hi>Tramboon</hi> ſort, is like the ſmall <hi>Cinnamon,</hi> ſomething of the ſame taſt, but not ſo ſtrong, but more woody, and of a worſe colour; all come from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cortex Cinnamomi.</head>
                  <p>CInnamon is a Bark of the <hi>Cinnamon</hi> Tree, which groweth upon the Iſland <hi>Zeylon,</hi> of a light bright Cinna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon colour, of a very hot, but very pleaſant odoriferovs taſt, of a fragrant ſcent in the very handling of it, in Pipes about a yard in length; the ſmalleſt and thinneſt Bark is generally beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cortex Citri.</head>
                  <p>CItron Peels come from <hi>Spain</hi> and <hi>Portugal;</hi> thoſe which look of a lively yellow colour and fragrant ſmell, are beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cortex Elatherii.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a Bark ſo called from the name of an Iſland which is in the <hi>Weſt-Indies;</hi> 'tis a round curled Bark, (ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing like <hi>Jeſuits</hi> Bark) of a very hot
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:104566:19"/> taſt, and fragrant ſmell when burned, therefore it is often uſed to ſweet-ſcent Tobacco.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cortex Eſulae Rad.</head>
                  <p>IS a ſmall bright Bark, growing in <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland, Germany,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cortex Granatorum.</head>
                  <p>ARe the Peels of Pomegranate-Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, of which, greateſt part are brought to us from <hi>Portugal;</hi> the largeſt, reddiſh without, and a bright yellow within, are to be preferred. They grow alſo abundantly in <hi>Turky, Italy, Egypt, France</hi> and <hi>Spain,</hi> and other parts of the World.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cowitch.</head>
                  <p>IS the down of a large Cod, like a Peaſe-cod, of a brown colour, like dark Cinnamon, the ſaid Cowitch being nothing elſe but a down covering the ſaid Cods, called Cowitch, becauſe of its provoking itching and ſcratching, is of no other uſe, but to play Tricks and Waggery with: It cometh from <hi>Jamaica.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="33" facs="tcp:104566:19"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Cortex Guajaci.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THe Bark of <hi>Lignum Vitae,</hi> or <hi>Lignum Guajacum,</hi> that which is freſh and new, and taken from the Tree, when it is alive and green, is to be preferred, though a great many uſe alſo the dry Bark; the <hi>Lignum Vitae</hi> groweth abundantly in <hi>Jamaica,</hi> and in moſt of the <hi>American</hi> Iſlands.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cortex Limonum.</head>
                  <p>LEmon Peels are gathered here from the Lemmons, thoſe in <hi>Holland</hi> and other parts, they import great quantities from <hi>Portugal;</hi> thoſe which are of a good colour and ſcent, are beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cortex Peruanus.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>JEſuites Bark, <hi>China chinna, quin quina, Caſcarello, Cortex Patrum,</hi> is the Bark of a Tree which groweth in <hi>Peru,</hi> the Bark being not too large, but from the ſmaller Twigs curled, a lively colour, a little more dark yellowiſh than Cinna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon, of a bitter taſte, breaking ſhin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly, ſometimes very rough, and a
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:104566:20"/> whitiſh outward Bark are to be choſen: That which is very thick, dark colour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and flat, is nothing near ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cortex Saſſafrae Lign.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THe Bark of <hi>Saſſafras</hi> is of a reddiſh bright colour, and ſtrong taſte: It is brought from <hi>New-England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cortex Tamariſci.</head>
                  <p>IS the Bark of a Tree which groweth in <hi>Germany,</hi> along the <hi>Rhine</hi> and <hi>Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nube,</hi> in gravelly places; it comes in large bundles, the Bark looking an Iron gray without, and light brown within.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cortex Winteranus.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>WInter Bark is a whitiſh Bark brought to us from the <hi>Weſt-Indies,</hi> of a very hot biting taſt, pretty large and thick of Subſtance.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cranium Humanum.</head>
                  <p>THe Scull of a Man ought to be of ſuch an one which dieth a violent Death, (as War, or Criminal Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion)
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:104566:20"/> and never buried: Therefore thoſe of <hi>Ireland</hi> are here beſt eſteemed, being very clean and white, and often covered over with Moſs.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cremor Tartari.</head>
                  <p>IS a refining, and boyling, and ſhooting of <hi>French Argol,</hi> which is brought to us in quantities from <hi>France,</hi> that which is beſt, looks very white and clear, not yellowiſh, and the nearer it reſembles Cryſtal Tartari, (which is made of <hi>Rheniſh</hi> Argol) the better it is to be eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Crocus Anglicus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ENgliſh</hi> Saffron is moſtly brought out of <hi>Cambridgeſhire,</hi> and gathered near <hi>Saffron<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>Walden,</hi> made up in Cakes; that which is of very fiery red, and blood red colour, of a very ſtrong ſmell, of a hottiſh taſt, ſtriking a very good Tin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture, of a large Leaf, tough and firm in the tearing, is to be preferred: That which is of a pale yellowiſh colour, old and decayed, is by nothing near ſo good, therefore the neweſt is to be cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen before any, unleſs the year before
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:104566:21"/> brought forth that which was larger, richer, and of a better colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Crocus Hiſpanicus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SPaniſh</hi> Saffron comes in looſe Leaves, and is generally oyled over; that which is of a large Leaf, good lively colour, and well ſcented, as above-ſaid, is to be choſen.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Crocus Martis.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation; being made of Iron by a Calcination in a Rever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beratory Fire, till it cometh off in a fine pure red <hi>Crocus.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Crocus Metallorum.</head>
                  <p>THe Saffron of Metalls is made of Antimony, Salnitre, (and ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times fine Tartar) put to a Fuſion and Detonation, the Faeces being ſeparated, produceth a fine Liver-coloured <hi>Crocus.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Cubebae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CUbebs</hi> is an Aromatick Fruit, ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what like to Pepper, being a little
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:104566:21"/> leſs, of a hot Aromatick taſt: They grow in the Iſle of <hi>Java,</hi> and are ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerally brought from <hi>Bantam.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cuſcuta.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>DOdder</hi> is an Herb which is inclining to a red colour, and very ſtalky; it groweth in moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Crystallus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CRystal</hi> is a ſtone much like to frozen Ice; that which is uſed in Phyſick ought to be pure, clear and whitiſh, tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſparent like Water; 'tis abundantly found in <hi>Germany, Bohemia, Hungaria, Cypres, France,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Chelae Cancrorum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CRabs-Claws</hi> are the tips of the lar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger Sea-Crabs gathered here in <hi>England,</hi> and near adjacent places, the largeſt being moſt deſired, being black on the tips, and red underneath.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cicerum Rub.</head>
                  <p>REd <hi>Cicer</hi> is a kind of a Pea of a bright freſh red colour, a little
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:104566:22"/> ſharp point at one end of it, full and large, and not black or dark; they come from <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Cicer Album.</head>
                  <p>IS the ſame as aforeſaid, being on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly of a white colour inſtead of red; they come from <hi>Italy,</hi> as the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Colocynthis.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>COloquintida,</hi> Coloquints is a wild Fruit, not unlike to Oranges, which being pared, is very white and light, full of Seeds, coming from <hi>Egypt,</hi> the taſte ſo bitter, even exceeding Gall.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Coculus Indus.</head>
                  <p>IS a Berry which is brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> a little more round and larger than Bay-berry, hollow within, and of a browniſh colour: They bring them likewiſe from <hi>Turky.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Colophonia.</head>
                  <p>IS nothing but a tranſparent, clear, and yellowiſh Reſin, which will eaſily
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:104566:22"/> be beaten into a (whitiſh) Powder: 'Tis brought to us from <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="d" type="part">
               <head>D.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Dactylus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>DAtes</hi> is a Fruit coming from <hi>Barbary,</hi> ſome from <hi>Aſia:</hi> The beſt are large, long in ſhape, yellow colour, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clining a little to red; (ſome a little darker) if the ſtone within is very white, and a little Cap upon their tops, ſhoweth that they are freſh, their taſte is ſweet, ſomewhat like to <hi>Malago-</hi>Wine.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Dens Apri.</head>
                  <p>THe Tuſh of a wild Boar is crooked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly bent, ſomething like to a Sea-horſe Tooth, but a great deal leſs; not above two or three Inches long, as white as Ivory, ſharp at one end, and hollow at the other: They come from <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="40" facs="tcp:104566:23"/>
                  <head>Dens Equi Marini.</head>
                  <p>THe Sea-horſe Tooth is of a large bigneſs, ſome of four, five, or ſix pound weight, crookedly bent like a Half-Moon, white like Ivory: They are found in the <hi>Weſt-Indies, Hudſons Bay, Greenland,</hi> and many other parts.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Diapente.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>DIapente,</hi> is a Compoſition made by every Druggiſt, for the uſe and cure of Horſes.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="e" type="part">
               <head>E.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Ebor. Raſurae.</head>
                  <p>THe ſhavings of Ivory, being made by the Ivory Comb-makers and Turners; the largeſt, whiteſt, and clean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt, are beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="41" facs="tcp:104566:23"/>
                  <head>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>lixir Proprietatis.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation made of the beſt of Saffron, Myrrh and Aloes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which is known by the taſt, as likewiſe by the good tincture from the Saffron.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Epithymum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>EPithymum,</hi> is a kind of a Dodder which groweth over Time, like a Silk, or a Cob-web, of a brown red<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſh colour, that which has a good fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant ſmell, and feweſt ſtalks, is to be preferred. It comes from <hi>Turky, Italy,</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Ens Veneris.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation made of Copper, Sal Armoniack, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> That which is good, is very light; of a yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowiſh Orange colour, is made here in Town.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="f" type="part">
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:104566:24"/>
               <head>F.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Flores Balauſt.</head>
                  <p>ARe the bloſſoms of the Pomegranate Tree, of a very lively Scarlet red colour, (though they are dried) pretty large, they come in great quantities from <hi>Turky,</hi> ſometimes alſo from <hi>Portugal, Italy</hi> and <hi>Spain,:</hi> They grow here in <hi>England,</hi> and many other parts.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Flores Chamaemeli.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CAmomil</hi> Flowers, of which the dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble is called <hi>Roman</hi> Camomil-Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, being moſt fragrant, and whiter than the ſingle, the ſame being yellow within, and white at the edge: They grow here in <hi>England, Germany,</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Flores Meliloti.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MElilot</hi> Flower is of a yellow co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, growing here in <hi>England,</hi> in ſtony places beſt: It is in its Flowers
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:104566:24"/> the whole Summer, the ſmell reſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling ſomewhat near to Honey.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Flores Origani.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ORiganum,</hi> the beſt which is liked of here in <hi>England,</hi> reſembleth the ſweet <hi>Marjarom,</hi> 'tis nothing elſe but a wild <hi>Marjarom,</hi> growing in <hi>Spain, Portu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal, Italy,</hi> and other hot Countries, of a fragrant ſmell, betwixt <hi>Marjarom</hi> and <hi>Time,</hi> being in knotty Flowers, and free from Stalks, and of a light browniſh co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour. It is generally brought from <hi>Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ice</hi> and <hi>Cadiz.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Flores Staechados.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SAechas</hi> is a Flower pretty large, (much of the ſhape of large Hops) of a fragrant ſmell when growing, the Flowers are yellow and blewiſh, but when dried up, of a Beer colour, or light brown in knobs: the largeſt not broken, well ſcented, are beſt, which come from the <hi>Straits, Italy</hi> and <hi>Spain:</hi> There is a blewiſh ſort which comes from <hi>Marſeilles,</hi> but is not ſo well liked of.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="44" facs="tcp:104566:25"/>
                  <head>Flores Sulphuris</head>
                  <p>IS nothing elſe but rough Brimſtone ſublimed by a Chymical way; it is to be choſen, that which is fine, light and ſoft, not harſh, of a fine lively yellow colour, almoſt inſipid in taſte, diſſolving in the Mouth.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Folia Betonicae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>BEtony</hi> Leaves are gathered here in <hi>England,</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> their Flowers being of a Purple colour; the beſt are thoſe which are gathered in <hi>May.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Folia Dictamni Cret.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>DIttany</hi> Leaves grow in <hi>Candia<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Dalmatia, Morea, &amp;c.</hi> the beſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> are in large Leaves, well covered with Willow-green, rough Cotton as it were upon them; ſometimes with Purple Flowers: Thoſe Leaves which are thi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> and bald, are to be rejected, they come from <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="45" facs="tcp:104566:25"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Folia Malabathri.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>FOlium Indiae, Folium Caſſiae,</hi> is brought to us from the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> groweth plentifully in <hi>Cambaja</hi> near the Water<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>de; the Leaf is large and broad, longer than a Lawrel leaf, not quite ſo broad; that is to be choſen which is green, of a ſtrong ſmell, Cinnamon like, and that which is freſh, not black or decayed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Folia Roſarum Rubrar.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>REd-Roſe-Leaves</hi> come out of <hi>France,</hi> ſometimes great ſto<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e are gathered in <hi>England,</hi> of a ſweet ſmell, lively, dark red colour, choice ought to be made.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Folia Scordii.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SCordium,</hi> or wild <hi>Germander,</hi> groweth in and near wateriſh places here in <hi>England,</hi> and many places of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Folia Sennae Aleppo.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALeppo Senna,</hi> is the courſeſt of all <hi>Senna,</hi> (except the <hi>Eaſt-India)</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing generally full of Stalks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of a ſhor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:104566:26"/> Leaf, it is to be choſen of a good ſtrong ſmell, not muſty, green, of a pal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> colour, and well cleanſed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Folia Sennae Alexand.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALexandria Senna,</hi> is the beſt of al<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>Senna,</hi> of a large and long leaf, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> freſh ſmell, free from Stalks, and ſmall<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> of a lively colour, and a very goo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> ſcent.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Folia Soldonellae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SEA-Colwort,</hi> or <hi>Bindweed,</hi> is an Her<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> of a green leaf, growing near Mari<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tim places in <hi>Italy, France</hi> and <hi>Zealand<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi> from thence 'tis brought to us.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Folia Tuſſilaginis.</head>
                  <p>THe leaves of <hi>Colts-foot</hi> grow her<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> in <hi>England,</hi> and moſt part of <hi>Eu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rope.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="g" type="part">
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:104566:26"/>
               <head>G.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gallae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GAuls,</hi> is a thing which groweth upon Oaks (of a certain kind) in <hi>Turky,</hi> more in uſe by Dyers and Salters, than Druggiſts; the beſt ſort are the <hi>Aleppo Gauls,</hi> and the beſt of them, thoſe which are blew and heavy, thoſe which are yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowiſh, inclining to red, (as moſt of the <hi>Smyrna</hi> ſort) are not ſo much eſteemed: They are brought from <hi>Turky.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Grana Paradiſi.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MAllagetta,</hi> is of a dark reddiſh co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, hot taſte like Pepper: They are brought from <hi>Guinea.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gutta Gamba.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CAmbogium, Gutta-Gum,</hi> is an inſpiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſated Juice of a Plant, but not well known of what Herb: The ſame is brought from <hi>China,</hi> the colour is not un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like to the fineſt <hi>Curcuma;</hi> a fine yellow,
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:104566:27"/> pure, inclining to an Orange colour<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> without Droſs, pure and clean, in round Rowles and Cakes, eaſily diſſolving, when touched with wet, or the Tongue, wil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> turn whitiſh, or of a milky Subſtance.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Ammoniacum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Gum-Ammoniack</hi> is in fine little drops, the beſt is looſe, ſomewhat like fine <hi>Olibanum,</hi> but in leſs drops, white within, and yellow without, ſmelling like to <hi>Caſtoreum,</hi> of a bitter taſte, it will eaſily ſtick to the Fingers, and ſo it often cometh all in one Maſs or Lump; it is brought from <hi>Turky</hi> and <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> growing near the place where the Oracle of <hi>Hammon</hi> was, from whence 'tis thought to take its name.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Animi.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>HEre that which is called <hi>Gum Animi,</hi> is called beyond the Seas <hi>Copal,</hi> and ſo <hi>Vice verſa;</hi> the Gum here meant, is hard, tranſparent, rough without, like <hi>Gum Senica;</hi> it is brought from <hi>Guinea.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="49" facs="tcp:104566:27"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Arabicum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GUm Arabick, Gummi Thebaicum, Gum Babylon</hi> cometh from a ſmall Tree growing near the Water, of a white, clear, and tranſparent colour: 'Tis brought to us from <hi>Turky,</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Aſa faetida.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>STinking <hi>Aſa</hi> (by ſome called Devils<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dirt) are the Tears (or Lachryma) of a Tree called <hi>Laſeris,</hi> growing in <hi>Sy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ria, Lybia,</hi> and <hi>Media,</hi> the fineſt is in pure fine, white and clean drops, free from Stalks and other mixture, of a very ſtrong foetid or ſtinking ſmell, even exceding Garlike; 'tis adulterated with flower <hi>Sagapenum, &amp;c.</hi> It is brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> and the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Gum Ceraſorum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GUM.</hi> from a Cherry-Tree is of a brown red colour, ſoftiſh and clammy; 'tis found iſſuing out of Cherry-trees here in <hi>England,</hi> and all parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="50" facs="tcp:104566:28"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Carannae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>G<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>m Caragna</hi> is a ſoftiſh reſinous <hi>Gum,</hi> being very tough, of a darkiſh Olive colour (inclining to a Musk co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour) being ſoft, condenſeth; being brought from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies,</hi> from a place called <hi>Cartagena,</hi> being of an odoriferous ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Copal.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a whitiſh ſoftiſh <hi>Gum</hi> (as it is here in <hi>England</hi> eſteemed) of an indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent good ſmell, inclining to a yellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh white colour, much like to the ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary <hi>Frankincenſe,</hi> but of a better ſmell; It comes from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Gum Bdellium.</head>
                  <p>'TIs the Tear (or Lachryma) of a thorny Tree growing in <hi>Arabia, India</hi> and <hi>Media,</hi> 'tis of a bitter taſte, fat in feeling, of a fragrant ſmell, ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what ſoftiſh, not eaſily to be beaten in a Mortar, of a light browniſh colour, (like bright and freſh <hi>Prunelloes)</hi> and ſome of it black.</p>
                  <pb n="51" facs="tcp:104566:28"/>
                  <p> There is another ſort which here is moſt deſired, which cometh amongſt <hi>Gum Senica,</hi> and a little reſembling it, or like large pieces of <hi>Olibanum,</hi> which is eaſily beaten into Powder, but by the Learned, not looked upon ſo true as the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Benzoin.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS very well ſcented, odoriferous and fragrant, the beſt is as if it were mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled, or intermixt with white and light brown, or dark yellowiſh ſpecks, break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing very eaſily, being rubbed betwixt the Hands, of a moſt pleaſant fragrancy; it may alſo be diſtinguiſhed by throwing ſome ſmall Powder upon Coal: It is ſaid to be found in <hi>Samaria</hi> and <hi>Sidon,</hi> but that which is brought to us, cometh from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi> There are ſeveral ſorts, and of ſeveral qualities, ſome gray and white, which is pretty good, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother ſort all grayiſh, little white, but inclining to a dark brown, full of Droſs, which is the worſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="52" facs="tcp:104566:29"/>
                  <head>Gum Elemi.</head>
                  <p>IS a <hi>Gum</hi> brought to us from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies,</hi> (ſome ſay alſo from <hi>Ae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thiopia)</hi> 'tis a very ſoft, bright, almoſt tranſparent <hi>Gum,</hi> white, inclining to yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low and green colour, ſo it ſeemed be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe of its moiſture and ſoftneſs, it cometh in longiſh Cakes, rouled up in flags, if lighted on a Candle, or Fire, there will exhale a ſweet Fragrancy.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Guajaci.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a <hi>Gum</hi> iſſuing out of a <hi>Lignum-vitae</hi> Tree, the beſt is in great pieces, clear like Roſin, and breaks as eaſily, but of a green colour, that which is very clear and clean, breaking green, not filled up with Droſs, (as ſome is) ought to be choſen: It cometh from <hi>Jamaica,</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther parts of the <hi>Weſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Galbanum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a fattiſh and glutinous <hi>Gum,</hi> gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally v<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>y moiſt, and of a ſtrong fla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour and ſmell, but <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ragrant and pleaſant withal, of a white, inclining to yellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:104566:29"/> colour, ſometimes full of little light Stalks and duſty; the cleareſt and pureſt is to be preferred, which cometh from <hi>Turky.</hi> Some hath lately been brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> which hath been much adulterated, and nothing near ſo good as the former.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Euphorbium.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the Gum of a thorny Tree growing in <hi>Barbary,</hi> from thence 'tis imported to us. The beſt is <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> like a middling ſort of <hi>Manna</hi> in ſmall Flakes, a little ſmell, but very pernici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous if taken, and hot in the Noſe, will ſet it (ſpeaking comparatively) all on a Fire.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Gum Hederae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GUM</hi> of <hi>Ivy</hi> is found in moſt part of <hi>Europe,</hi> as alſo here in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Gum Juniperi,</head>
                  <p>OR <hi>Gum Sandaraca,</hi> cometh from <hi>Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bary,</hi> being in little longiſh tears or drops of a yellowiſh colour, almoſt tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſparent, very hard, and if beaten, it
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:104566:30"/> will run in a very fine Powder, (which is called <hi>Pounce)</hi> 'tis abundantly uſed in Varniſh, gilding of Leather, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Lacca.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS ſaid to be the Juice of a Tree, which is ſaid to be gathered by flying or winged Ants, (like as Bees do honey out of Flowers) which they induce about the Twigs and Branches of Trees. And thus we ſee ſtick I <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> to us: 'Tis of a redd<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>ght colour, not unlike to ſmall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ed Myrrh; that which is called <hi>Seed Lack,</hi> is in ſmall, bright reddiſh grains; the beſt is moſt brighteſt, inclining to a yellowiſh colour, it ſmells ſweetiſh when burnt, (though unwholſome) <hi>Shell Lack</hi> is made out of <hi>Seed Lack,</hi> being melted down of the fineſt <hi>Lack,</hi> and if fine, is of a reddiſh colour, and almoſt tranſparent. It cometh from <hi>Martaba, Malavar,</hi> and <hi>Sumatra</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Labdanum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS ſaid to be a liquor (or rather a Juice) out of a Tree called <hi>Ledon,</hi> of a blackiſh colour, cometh from <hi>Cypres</hi> in lumps, (which is generally the beſt) or in Pigs-tails,
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:104566:30"/> rolled up in round turſted Cakes (which are generally of a fragrant ſmell; but full of Sands) eſpecially when burnt, that which is fat, gummy, eaſily molli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied, is beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Myrrha.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MYrrh</hi> is a reſinous gummy Juice which groweth out of a Tree, of which they open the Bark, from thence it floweth in little and bigger drops, of a bright, fattiſh, and yellowiſh colour, of a fragrant ſmell and bitter taſte, ſmooth and bright, not too heavy, the black and cruſty is not ſo good; 'tis ſaid to come from <hi>Arabia,</hi> but we have it brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Olibanum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>'TIs the true and right, the beſt are in little round white-yellowiſh drops, inclining a little to red, being in looſe drops, and not run together; the beſt cometh from the <hi>Straits,</hi> very good com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth likewiſe from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> but ſome of it being run together in lumps and turned black, being nothing near ſo much eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="56" facs="tcp:104566:31"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Opopanax.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>OPopanax</hi> is a fine reddiſh fragrant <hi>Gum,</hi> 'tis gathered from a Root, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Juice of it, which thickned in the product; the beſt is in round looſe drops, but being very glutinous, it will ſtick together in lumps; the beſt cometh from the <hi>Straits</hi> and <hi>Turky,</hi> and very good has been brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> though of late they have very much adulterated the ſame in thoſe parts, <hi>viz.</hi> with <hi>Saga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>num,</hi> and <hi>Gum Ammoniacum.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Sagapenum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SAgapenum,</hi> the Juice of <hi>Serapin,</hi> is a drop, or a <hi>Gum</hi> out of a Tree, grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the Regions of <hi>Media,</hi> and ſome from <hi>Alexandria,</hi> being ſincere, very clear, the outward colour yellowiſh and reddiſh, inwardly white, of a ſharp taſte, grave ſmell, a little reſembling <hi>Garlick.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Sarcocolla.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a very ſmall Lachryma in little grains <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ot much bigger than Gravel, of a yellow, reddiſh colour, of a bitteriſh and
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:104566:31"/> ſweetiſh taſte, (like Liquoriſh) it runs out of a thorny Tree, being excorticated; 'tis brought to us from the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Styrax Cal.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>STorax Calamita, (à cannarum Calamis ſic dicta)</hi> is the <hi>Gum</hi> of a T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ee, being a reſinous Juice, fat, ſoft in hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, of a moſt ſweet fragrant ſmell, of a reddiſh colour, being mix'd with Bran is the worſe for it; ſome with Saw duſt, which is the worſt of all. This is gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally brought from <hi>Turky</hi> and <hi>Alexandria.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Senica.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GUM Senica,</hi> is a Gum which com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth from <hi>Guinea,</hi> growing near a River called <hi>Senica,</hi> coming in large round Knobs, ſome reddiſh, ſome whitiſh, breaking very clear with<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>n and rough without: 'Tis brought to us from <hi>Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> and <hi>France,</hi> becauſe our <hi>African</hi> Company have no admittance in thoſe parts from whence they bring it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="58" facs="tcp:104566:32"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Tacamahaca.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>OF which there is two ſorts, one is brought over in ſhells, which is ſoft and whitiſh, of a moſt pleaſant and fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant ſmell; the other in lumps, cometh in Cheſts, which is nothing near ſo good, being generally droſſie; both come from <hi>New Spain.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Gum Tragacanthum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GUM Traganth,</hi> is a Gum which is brought from <hi>Turky;</hi> the beſt is ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry white, in little ſmall and curled Sprigs, that which is thick, brown and yellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh, is of little value; it will eaſily diſſolve and turn into a <hi>Mucilage, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Gluten Oris.</head>
                  <p>MOuth Glew is made of <hi>Icing Glaſs, Gum Senica</hi> and <hi>Traganth,</hi> in little long pieces, above an Inch and a half in length.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="59" facs="tcp:104566:32"/>
                  <head>Granadillas Peru.</head>
                  <p>THe <hi>Granadilla</hi> is a black Berry (a ſort of <hi>Cataputia)</hi> of a longiſh ſhape, a little bigger than a <hi>Pine</hi> Kernel, of a black grayiſh Husk, a white Kernel within, (like the <hi>Barbados</hi> Nuts) not ſpeckled, but more a black colour, one half kernel being able to purge any body both upward and downward; they are light, and not heavy, and come from <hi>Peru</hi> in <hi>America.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="h" type="part">
               <head>H.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Hordeum Gallicum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>FRench Barley,</hi> ſo called, becauſe it uſed to be brought out of <hi>France;</hi> 'tis no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing elſe but a Barley excorticated, or the upper Husk taken off by a certain Mill, which is made for that purpoſe; that which is round, white and clear, is the beſt: The ſame is now made here, and in <hi>Holland</hi> and <hi>Germany, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="60" facs="tcp:104566:33"/>
                  <head>Hordeum Perlatum.</head>
                  <p>PEarl <hi>Barley,</hi> ſo called, becauſe it doth very much reſemble the larger ſort of Seed-Pearl, being very round and ſmall, white, well-flowred over, freſh, and not muſty, the ſmaller the better, 'tis likewiſe done as aforeſaid, but twice or thrice over to make it the finer, the beſt cometh from <hi>Germany,</hi> and in all, uſed to be preferred before the <hi>French Barley.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="i" type="part">
               <head>I.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Ichthyocolla.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Icing-Glaſs</hi> (in High-Dutch, <hi>Hauſon blaſs,</hi> Low-Dutch, <hi>Huyſen blaſſen)</hi> is the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct of a great Fiſh in the <hi>Danube,</hi> called in Latin <hi>Huſo,</hi> of a glewy ſubſtance, without Bones, or griſſel Bones, (except in the Head) ſometimes four and twenty foot in length, and without Scales, he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing deſirous of freſh-water, cometh out of the <hi>Euxine</hi> Sea into the <hi>Danube,</hi> moſt Icing Glaſs is made in <hi>Muſcovy;</hi> the beſt
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:104566:33"/> is the <hi>Patriarch</hi> ſort, four ſquare, very thin and white, almoſt tranſparent, the large Horſe-ſhooe ſort in thin Rings, and clear, called the <hi>Czars</hi> ſort, is the next; that which is yellow and brown within, a thick ſort, is inferiour; that in ſquare Books or Cakes, the worſt of all.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Jujubae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JUjubes</hi> is the fruit of a Tree called <hi>Zi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ziphus,</hi> of the bigneſs of a large <hi>Luke</hi> Olive, of a red colour like a Cherry, of taſt of Raiſins of the Sun, having a Stone within like Prunes; the beſt are plum full of Pulp, and come from <hi>Italy;</hi> there is another ſort cometh from <hi>France,</hi> which are lean and hungry, a lighter red colour, but nothing near ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Juncus Odoratus.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SQuinanth,</hi> alias <hi>Camelshay,</hi> is brought from <hi>Turky,</hi> and ſaid to grow in <hi>Ara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bia;</hi> that which is good, is of a ſtrong Aromatick ſmell, is well colour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, bright, of a good length, being often times made up in ſmall bundles, of a Py<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ramid faſhion; the ſhort, grayiſh, and knotty ſort, is nothing near ſo much to be eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="l" type="part">
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:104566:34"/>
               <head>L.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lac Sulphuris.</head>
                  <p>IS made of Flower of <hi>Brimſtone,</hi> and Salt of <hi>Tartar,</hi> by a Chymical Prepara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Amethyſtus.</head>
                  <p>THE <hi>Amethyst</hi> Stone, is of a dark Peach, or a live and light Purple, but a great deal paler; the beſt is of the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> or Oriental ſort, which is fit to be ſet in Rings, the other, and that which we uſe in Phyſick, is courſer, and not ſo well coloured, which is brought to us out of <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Amianthus.</head>
                  <p>IS a reddiſh Stone, the beſt coming from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> thoſe which come from <hi>Bohemia,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Germany,</hi> are not ſo good: This Stone is of very little uſe, and very little ſold amongſt <hi>Druggiſts.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="63" facs="tcp:104566:34"/>
                  <head>Lapis Armenus.</head>
                  <p>THE <hi>Armenian</hi> Stone is of ſeveral ſpots, green, blewiſh, gold-colour'd, and a little inclining to black; this Stone is ſo called, becauſe it is brought from <hi>Armenia.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis Bezoar Occidentalis.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THE <hi>Weſt-India Bezoar,</hi> cometh moſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies,</hi> of ſeveral ſizes and bigneſs, ſome bigger than a Turky-Hens-Egg, others no bigger than a Haſel-Nut, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The right is of an Aſh-gray colour, ſome inclining to black; it ſhivers pieces from pieces, as well as the Oriental <hi>Bezoar,</hi> though in vertue by fair inferiour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis Bezoar Orientalis.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>ORiental <hi>Bezoar</hi> is found in the inner parts of a Beaſt, of ſeveral Forms and Shapes, ſome round, Oval, longiſh and ſquare, and ſometimes in it a ſtraw, a bean, a ſtalk, a myrobalan Kernel, a Hair and pibble Stone; They are of ſeveral bigneſs, thoſe in ſort not exceeding a
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:104566:35"/> dram; others of half, or one Ounce, but thoſe of two and three Ounces, are Rari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties: They are of a dark green Olive colour, ſmooth and gliſſening.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Calaminaris.</head>
                  <p>IS a grayiſh Stone, inclining to yellow and red; 'tis very heavy, and uſed in the making Braſs out of Copper; and this Stone it comes from <hi>Germany,</hi> and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral other parts, as alſo from <hi>Briſtol</hi> and others parts of <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis Contrayerva.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a made Stone of <hi>Contrayerva-Roots,</hi> Pearls, Coral, Amber, Crabs-eyes, and ſeveral other Ingredients, which after is gilded over, ſmelleth ſtrong of the Root.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Dentalis.</head>
                  <p>ARE littte bones out of a <hi>Haddock,</hi> or large <hi>Whiting,</hi> having two in every Head, they have as it were little Teeth at one ſide of them, from which, I ſuppoſe the name is derived.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="65" facs="tcp:104566:35"/>
                  <head>Lapis Gagates.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JEtt,</hi> or <hi>Gett,</hi> is a bituminous Stone, very ſhining and hard; 'tis ſo called from <hi>Gaga,</hi> a River in <hi>Sicily:</hi> It comes like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe from <hi>Aſia</hi> and <hi>Turky.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis de Goa.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GOA</hi> Stones, (by ſome not rightly called <hi>Lapis Jaſpar Antonicus)</hi> is a made Stone, (by the <hi>Portugees</hi> of <hi>Goa,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the chief place the <hi>Portugoiſe</hi> have near <hi>China</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies)</hi> ſome ſay of Seed-pearl, <hi>Bezoar,</hi> Gold, and other In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gredients; they are of a dark green co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, mixed with Gold Streaks, in ſhape almoſt of a large Olive, cutting very fine within, of a gray colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Granatas.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GRanat</hi> is a dark reddiſh Stone, ſome as large as a ſmall Piſtol-ſhot, others are ſmall like <hi>Guinea</hi> Grains: There is a great many found in <hi>Bohemia,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Germany,</hi> the cleareſt, and redeſt like Rubies, are the beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="66" facs="tcp:104566:36"/>
                  <head>Lapis Haematites.</head>
                  <p>SOme call it Blood-ſtone, being of a blood red colour; the beſt are long, and do ſhiver ſharp at one end, like a Needle: They are found in <hi>Bohemia</hi> and <hi>Sileſia,</hi> near <hi>Breſlaw.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Hyacinthus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>HYacinth</hi> Stones are of a light brown, or Beer colour, the beſt are ſmall, flat, and a rough outſide: There is a large ſort, which looks as if they were cut or polliſhed, of a red colour: The Oriental and beſt, are finer than both, of the co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour of red fiery Flames. The former are found near a River in <hi>Sileſia,</hi> the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther come from <hi>France,</hi> and the beſt from <hi>East-India.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Jaſpis.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>IAſper</hi> Stone, is of a reddiſh colour, (and not as ſome ſay, of a green in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terwoven with red ſpots) it comes from the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="67" facs="tcp:104566:36"/>
                  <head>Lapis Judaicus.</head>
                  <p>IS a longiſh Stone of the bigneſs of a Finger; ſome ſhorter, 'tis of a gray colour; thoſe which come from <hi>Syria</hi> are beſt eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Lazuli.</head>
                  <p>IS a blewiſh Stone, of a moſt excellent colour if fine, (of which <hi>Ultramarine</hi> is made) ſome are with Golden (or rather Braſs) Veins interwoven; the courſer is mixt with white, like rough Alabaiſter; the beſt is that which holds its colour in Fire, and comes from the <hi>East-Indies</hi> and <hi>Turky;</hi> That which is found in <hi>Germany,</hi> is nothing near ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Lyncis.</head>
                  <p>IS a Stone of various colour, but mo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>t betwixt a gray and brown, ſharp at one end like an Arrow, and Pyramid faſhion, the bigneſs of a little Finger: They are found in <hi>Candia, Pomerania, Helvetia,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="68" facs="tcp:104566:37"/>
                  <head>Lapis Magnes.</head>
                  <p>LOad-ſtone is of an Iron colour, and looks ſometimes ruſty; if good, it will draw Iron ſtrongly to it, by vertue of which, Sailers and Mariners find out all parts of the World: 'Tis found near Iron Mines, in <hi>Norway, Germany, Italy, Sweedland,</hi> and <hi>Cornwal</hi> here in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis Manateae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LApis Manateae,</hi> is a whitiſh bone of a Fiſh called <hi>Manatea,</hi> which is plenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful in <hi>America</hi> and the <hi>Weſt-Indies,</hi> viz. St. <hi>Chriſtopher</hi>'s, <hi>Mevis, Jamaica,</hi> &amp;c. It is very white and hard, like a Stone, ſomewhat reſembling white Ivory.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Nephriticus.</head>
                  <p>IS a grayiſh Stone, inclining to a pale green; it comes out of New and Old <hi>Spain,</hi> likewiſe from ſome parts of <hi>Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>many,</hi> of which one has been ſeen weigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing fifty Pound and more at <hi>Francf<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>rt.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="69" facs="tcp:104566:37"/>
                  <head>Lapis Oſtiocolla</head>
                  <p>IS of a whitiſh colour, very rough, in ſhape like the Pipe of a mans Bone; 'tis found in the <hi>Palatinate, Darmſtad,</hi> and in <hi>Saxo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Sapphirus</head>
                  <p>IS of a Steel colour, in very ſmall pieces, that ſort comes from <hi>Germany,</hi> and is uſed in Phyſick; but the Oriental <hi>Sapphire</hi> is of a moſt curious blew colour, which is ſet in Rings, and is brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Rubinus</head>
                  <p>IS of a pure, fine, red, fiery colour; that which is Phyſically uſed, is very ſmall, like Gravel, but of blood red colour; the harder they are, the better they are rec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>koned: The ſmall ones which are uſed, come out of <hi>Germany, Bohemia</hi> and <hi>Italy;</hi> the large Oriental Rubies, being Jewels of great worth, come from <hi>Zeylon,</hi> and other parts of the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="70" facs="tcp:104566:38"/>
                  <head>Lapis Sardus.</head>
                  <p>IS of a fleſhy colour, therefore ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times (though corruptly) <hi>Carneol;</hi> they are found in <hi>Egypt, Arabia,</hi> and likewiſe very good ones in <hi>Bohemia</hi> and <hi>Sileſia.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis Smaragdus.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>EMerauld</hi> Stone, are (if good) of a very fine green and lively colour, eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally thoſe which are the Oriental; the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther which come out of <hi>Egypt, &amp; Germany,</hi> are far inferiour, being ſometimes mixt with white and purple <hi>Amethysts.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Topaſius.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>TOpas</hi> Stones, ſome are very hard, and if fine and a good luſtre, they reſemble a Diamond, the neareſt of any others; more ſoft, reſemble Cryſtals, and ſo are thoſe which are found in <hi>Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hemia;</hi> They are likewiſe called <hi>Chry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolithus.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="71" facs="tcp:104566:38"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Lapis Tutia</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a dark grayiſh Stone, very rough on the one ſide, and hollow and ſmooth on the other; 'tis ſaid to be the Exfulmi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of Braſs Mettal, but I rather be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve it Natural: They are brought from the <hi>Eaſt Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis ex felle Bovis.</head>
                  <p>IS a little Stone found in the gall of an <hi>Oxe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Spongiae.</head>
                  <p>ARe little white Stones which are found amongſt the Sponges, being ſuppoſed to be that which faſtneth the Sponges to the Rocks: They come from the <hi>Gulph L<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>panto.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Aetites.</head>
                  <p>THe <hi>Eagle</hi> Stone is of two ſorts; the Oriental is of the bigneſs of a Prune, or a Plumb, of a yellowiſh gray colour, the other of divers ſhapes and bigneſs, are found near <hi>Sweinford</hi> in <hi>Germany.</hi> They
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:104566:39"/> have another Stone within (as it were pregnant) which rattles, thoſe are of an Iron colour, rough without, ſome of them are poliſhed; they are found in the Neſt of an Eagle. Women with Child carry them under the left Arm, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout them, to hinder Miſcarriage and Abortion.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lapis Hibernus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>IRiſh</hi> ſlate, is a ſoftiſh Stone which is eaſily ſcraped to a Powder; 'tis of an Aſh-blew colour, inclining to black.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Aloes.</head>
                  <p>IS brought from <hi>Bantam,</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and is by them called <hi>Colum-back;</hi> 'tis of a moſt fragrant ſmell, and of a darkiſh colour; the knotty, reſinous, and blackeſt ſort, which is ſometimes full of black reſin, like Aloes, is to be choſen.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lignum Aſpalathum</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>COmes likewiſe from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> in great pieces, much reſembling <hi>Lignum Aloes,</hi> but ſomewhat of a lighter
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:104566:39"/> colour, but nothing near ſo fragrant nor good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lignum Guajacum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LIgnum Vitae,</hi> looks greeniſh and blew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh within, and white without; 'tis very heavy, and cometh from <hi>Jamaica,</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Weſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Juniperi.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JUniper</hi> Wood groweth here in <hi>England,</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> 'tis very well ſcented, like the Berries, if cut in <hi>March.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Lignum Lentiſcinum.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the Wood of a <hi>Maſtich</hi> Tree, which cometh from <hi>Marſeilles</hi> in the ſhapes of Faggot-ſticks, when raſp'd, it will ſmell a little like <hi>Mastic:</hi> The ſmal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſt ſprigs of all are beſt eſteemed. It groweth likewiſe in <hi>Italy,</hi> and great quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tities in <hi>Chio.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Nephriticum.</head>
                  <p>IS a Wood which is blew within, and white without; to know whether it
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:104566:40"/> be right, is to ſcrape ſome of the inner Wood, and let it ſtand for four or five hours in Water, it will turn the ſaid Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter into a blewiſh Tincture, which will ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear above; 'tis brought from <hi>Mexico,</hi> the <hi>Spaniſh West-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Rhodium.</head>
                  <p>'TIs by ſome called Roſen Wood, not that any Roſes do grow upon it, but that the Wood has much the ſame fragrancy; the beſt is very fat, of a deep yellowiſh colour, inclining to red, is of a very ſtrong ſmell, and if broken, of an oyly ſubſtance; 'tis brought from the <hi>Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naries.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Santalum Album.</head>
                  <p>VVHite <hi>Sanders</hi> Wood is brought from the <hi>East-Indies,</hi> is of a very little ſmell, in long ſticks as big as a Leg.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Santalum Citrium.</head>
                  <p>YEllow <hi>Sanders</hi> cometh likewiſe from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> being very fragrant, and of a ſweet ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="75" facs="tcp:104566:40"/>
                  <head>Lignum Santalum Rubrum.</head>
                  <p>REd <hi>Sanders,</hi> is a red and heavy Wood (called in <hi>Holland, Caliatours</hi> Wood) it is brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> and if ground, is a very fine red Powder.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lignum Saſſafras.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SAſſafras</hi> Wood, is rather a Root than Wood, of a pleaſant ſmell; the beſt is in long Sticks, ſtreight, and not jumpy; the Bark without is very red, and cuts of a Fleſh colour within.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lithargyrus Argenti.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LItharge</hi> of Silver is whitiſh, and in lumps, very heavy, ſhining and gli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtering, eaſily broken in ſhivers if good, if otherwiſe, 'tis hard and rocky; 'tis a made thing out of Lead: The beſt of it is made in <hi>Poland;</hi> that which is made in <hi>Germany</hi> is nothing near ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Lithargyrus Auri.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LItharge</hi> of Gold is made like the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer of Lead, being ſmaller than
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:104566:41"/> that of Silver, of a redder colour, more reſembling to Gold; 'tis not improperly called the foam of Lead; there is no o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther difference betwixt both ſorts, than that the <hi>Litharge</hi> of Gold is more boyl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed: The beſt cometh from <hi>Dantzick,</hi> and is of a fine reddiſh colour.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="m" type="part">
               <head>M.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Magiſterium Corallior.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MAgiſtery</hi> of Coral, is a Chymical Preparation made of red Coral and diſtilled Vinegar, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whereby the Coral is reduced into a fine Powder, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt inpalpable. Some make it in lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle Casks, but it is nothing the better for it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Magiſterium Perlarum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MAgiſtery</hi> of Pearls is likewiſe prepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red of Pearls, as aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="77" facs="tcp:104566:41"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Margaritae Occitendal.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>OCcidental</hi> Pearls, ſo called, becauſe they are not of that Oriental Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtre, brightneſs, nor ſmoothneſs, as the Oriental Pearls; They come from <hi>Surrat</hi> and the coaſt of the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> being a Seed Pearl which is more obſcure or mud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy than the Oriental; the beſt are round, even, of a ſhining Luſtre: There is a large ſcrubbed, and rough ſort, which are the leaſt eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Margaritae Orientales.</head>
                  <p>ORiental Pearls, the beſt are of a fine luſtrous oriental Water, of an e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven ſize, round and ſmooth, ſomething harder than the Occidental ſort; They come from the <hi>East-Indies,</hi> as aforeſaid, the beſt from <hi>Perſia.</hi> There is another ſort called the South-Sea Pearls, they are very ſmooth, of a more whiter and paler colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Margaritae Scotiae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SCotch</hi> Pearls are pretty good, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ound, ſmooth and even, but very hard,
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:104566:42"/> not eaſily beaten into a Powder, not ſo luſtrous, but more of a Copper and Leadiſh dull colour, than any of the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid: They come from <hi>Scotland, Chester</hi> and <hi>Wales.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Manna.</head>
                  <p>IS a Dew falling out of the Air, upon the Branches and Twigs of Trees, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Herbs and Stones, and there it hard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neth; the large, bright, and flaky ſort, dry and whitiſh, very little inclining to a yellow, is beſt eſteemed.: This is found and gathered in <hi>Syria, Perſia, Calabria;</hi> and though ſome have eſteemed that of <hi>Syria</hi> beſt, yet the <hi>Calabrian</hi> is with us moſt preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Mater Perlarum.</head>
                  <p>MOther of Pearls; the beſt cometh from the <hi>East-Indies</hi> in large ſhells, the nearer it reſembleth Pearls, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in large ſmooth ſhells, the better: There is ſome found in <hi>Jarſey</hi> and <hi>Guern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſey,</hi> full of Holes, ſcruffy without, but they are of little value.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="79" facs="tcp:104566:42"/>
                  <head>Mandibula Lucii.</head>
                  <p>THe Jaw-bones of a Pike, are long and white, the Teeth as ſharp as Needles, are found here in <hi>England,</hi> and all parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Mastich.</head>
                  <p>IS a ſmall Gum which cometh from the ſame Tree, out of which we have the <hi>Chio Turpentine,</hi> and therefore by many called Oyl of Maſtich, growing in <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gypt, Syria,</hi> and other parts of <hi>Turky,</hi> as al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo the Iſle of <hi>Chio:</hi> The beſt <hi>Mastich</hi> is of a light colour, almoſt tranſparent, free from Droſs: It is brought to us from <hi>Smyrna</hi> and <hi>Aleppo.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Mel Anglicanum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ENgliſh</hi> Honey is the product of Bees, of a pale yellow colour, of a lively ſmell and taſte, of a good body, not greaſie, the (white) Virgins Honey is ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counted the beſt; the yellow is inferiour to the white Honey, is gathered in all parts of <hi>Europe, Aſia</hi> and <hi>Affrica.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="80" facs="tcp:104566:43"/>
                  <head>Mercurius Dulcis.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation by way of Sublimation of Quick-Silver and Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cury corroſive, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> If duly ſublimed it will be very white and clear, the inſide ſharp, and longiſh like Needles, and of a ſweet taſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Mercurius Sublimatus.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SUblimate</hi> is alſo a Chymical Preparation, the beſt, very white and ſhining, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and comes from <hi>Venice</hi> in large Cakes, which are better than any made elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Mercurius Praecipitatus.</head>
                  <p>MErcury Praecipitate is likewiſe Chy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mically prepared of Quick-Silver, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The beſt is heavy, of a very lively fine, red and gliſtering, even beyond Vermilion: The beſt cometh from <hi>Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nice,</hi> that which is made here and in <hi>Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> is not ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="81" facs="tcp:104566:43"/>
                  <head>Mercurius Vitae.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation, made out of Quick Silver, Antimony, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Myrobalani Bellerici.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a round Mirabolane: They are much like ſome Gauls, of a yellowiſh colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Myrobalani Chebuli.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MYrobalani Chebuli,</hi> are the largeſt of Myrabolanes, of a yellowiſh co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, and a long ſize, well filled and large.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Myrobalani Citrinae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>ARE much like the aforeſaid <hi>Chebu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>li,</hi> but a great deal leſs and ſmal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, longiſh, and of a yellowiſh colour. All Myrobalanes come from <hi>Surrat</hi> in the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Mirabolanes Emblici.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THeſe <hi>Myrobalanes</hi> are of a blackiſh colour, growing naturally in ſeveral pieces, as if they were ſliced or cut ſo.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="82" facs="tcp:104566:44"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Myrobalani Indae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THough all <hi>Myrobalanes</hi> come from the <hi>East-Indies,</hi> yet there is one ſort which is called by the name <hi>Indian Myro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>balan,</hi> being very ſmall, and almoſt eight cornered, of a black colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Moſchus.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MUsk</hi> is an Excremental Excreſcence, or a ſwelling of corrupted blood, about the Navle of a Musk Goat or Buck, (and not a Cat) which after Putrefaction and Ripening, turns to Musk in a per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect Cod, which is ſaid falls off of the Creature: The beſt is the <hi>Tonquin</hi> or <hi>Chi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na</hi> Musk, in thin Cods, well filled, round, and with little ſhort Hairs, the Musk within of a good lively Musk colour, ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſtrong, ſweet ſmell, ſomething moiſt, of a ſtrong taſt, a little bitteriſh. The <hi>Agria</hi> and <hi>Bengale</hi> Musk, is in thick Cods, long hair'd, a great deal of skin, and not half ſo full of Musk as the former; the Musk neither ſo good nor fragrant. The <hi>Ruſſia</hi> Musk is worſe than any, being courſe, of a dark colour, great Tare and little Musk: Thoſe Musk Cods which
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:104566:44"/> have been opened and ſowed again, are very ſuſpicious of adulteration; for there is often found Lead, Stones, Leather, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſtuffed in the Cods, amongſt the Musk, and that ſo cunningly, that it can hardly be perceived.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Mumia.</head>
                  <p>THe <hi>Arabian Mumia,</hi> is a Liquor ſweating out of dead Bodies, being Imbalmed with Aloes, Myrrh and Bal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſom, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> wrapped up in Cere-cloths: Sometimes whole Bodies may be ſeen, with Hands, Legs and Toes, perfectly intire, being of a black colour: And that <hi>Mumia</hi> which is moſt gummy or bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuminous, is beſt eſteemed. 'Tis brought from <hi>Chio</hi> and <hi>Egypt.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="n" type="part">
               <head>N.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Nuces è Barbadoes.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>BArbadoes</hi> Nuts, is nothing elſe but a large <hi>Cartaputia,</hi> which provokes Vomit vehemently, and ſometimes works by Stool; ſome are of a blackiſh Husk,
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:104566:45"/> ſome ſpeckled, they are larger than a French Bean, and have a very white Kernel within.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Nuces de Ben.</head>
                  <p>BEN Nuts, is of the bigneſs of a round large Haſel Nut, of a grayiſh Husk, a white Oleaginous Kernel within, out of which Oyl is drawn, like as out of Almonds They are brought from <hi>Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>key,</hi> viz. <hi>Smyrna</hi> and <hi>Aleppo.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Nuces Cupruſſi.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CYpreſs</hi> Nuts are of a longiſh ſhape, ſomething reſembling thoſe of a Fir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tree, being more cloſe and not ſo open. They are gathered here in <hi>England</hi> and other parts of <hi>Europe,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Nuces Piſtaechiae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>PIſtachies is a little ſmall longiſh Nut, the Kernel within, if freſh, is very Red, and the outſide and the inſide very Green, of a moſt pleaſant taſte; the hard Shell is very White and Greeniſh, inclin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to a Red, with a Husk over it. They grow in <hi>Perſia, Arabia, Syria,</hi> and are
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:104566:45"/> brought from <hi>Aleppo</hi> and <hi>Smyrna</hi> in <hi>Turkey.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Nuces Vomicae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>TIS</hi> a flat round Nut, almoſt as big as a Leaden Half-penny, a little hollow in the middle, which is brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi> It will infatuate any flying Foul or Bird, as likewiſe ſome other Creatures, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Nuces Indicae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THIS Nut is in ſhape like a Nutmeg, in chawing turns Red; 'tis ſaid they will make one Drunk in taking them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardly, but I could never find it. The People in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> chawing them for Refreſhment or Recreation, as we do Tobacco.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Nuclei Pinei.</head>
                  <p>PINE Kernel, is a black and longiſh Kernel, ſomething leſs than a Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berry, and a very white Kernel, Oily like an Almond within. They come from <hi>France</hi> by the way of <hi>Marſeilles.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="86" facs="tcp:104566:46"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Nuces Moſchatae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THE Nutmeg is a Fruit of two kinds, the Maſculine (a long and large Nut ſeldom uſed) the Foeminine a round and leſſer Nut, which are laid in quick Lime, that the Worms ſhould not take them. The beſt are new of a fatiſh ſubſtance, of a full roundneſs and hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vyneſs, not lean nor ſcraggy, of a grate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful taſte, and not hollow within; they are carried from an Iſland called <hi>Band<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> to <hi>Batava,</hi> and from thence, as well as all other Spices, brought to <hi>Holland,</hi> and from thence they are imported by the King's Licenſe: And ſo is Mace, Cloves, and Cinnamon, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="o" type="part">
               <head>O.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oculi Cancrorum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CRabs</hi> Eyes, (improperly ſo called, for they have none) but cray Fiſh Eyes (in the <hi>German Crebtz)</hi> of which there is ſome of a large bigneſs, as big as the
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:104566:46"/> 
                     <hi>Cheſter Lobſters,</hi> which have every one two Stones, or Crabs Eyes in the fore part of the Head, even beyond their Eyes. In <hi>Sileſia</hi> they have vaſt quanti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, inſomuch, that the Servants do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition but to eat ſo many times in a Week: There are ſtore of Cray Fiſh like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe in <hi>Poland.</hi> They are brought from <hi>Dantzick, Hamburgh,</hi> and other Sea Ports of <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Abſinthii.</head>
                  <p>OYL of <hi>Wormword</hi> is a Chymical Diſtillation, <hi>per Alembicum,</hi> of the ſame Herb; the Oyl of it is of a very dark colour, ſmelling ſtrong of Wormwood; very hot, and pretty heavy, ſinking un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der Water half way.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Aniſi.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn from Anniſeed in <hi>Germany.</hi> The beſt is very white, congealed like a hard Snow, ſmelling ſtrong of the Anniſeed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Amygdalarum Amar.</head>
                  <p>OYL of bitter Almonds, is drawn by a ſtrong Screw-Preſs from bitter
<pb n="88" facs="tcp:104566:47"/> Almonds. The Oyl is nevertheleſs ſweet; the beſt is when new and clear.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Amygdalarum Dulc.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn from ſweet Almonds, as the Oyl aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Aſparis.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl drawn from a Bird, called <hi>Aſper,</hi> whoſe ſcent is ſaid to be ſo ſtrong, that Fiſhes are drawn by the ſcent as he is flying over the River, and ſo taken up by him, having one leg like a Hawk, the other like a Duck.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Auranti<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>rum.</head>
                  <p>OYL of <hi>Oranges,</hi> is drawn from the upper rind, or Peel of Sevil Oran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, by a Chymical way, <hi>per Alembicum.</hi> The beſt is of a moſt pure, fragrant ſmell, like the beſt Sevil Oranges.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum de Ben.</head>
                  <p>OYL of <hi>Ben</hi> is made by Expreſſion, out of the inner Kernel of a <hi>Ben</hi> Nut. The Oyl is more of condenſed
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:104566:47"/> Body, and will keep longer than any Oyl of Almonds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Carvi.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl of <hi>Carvi</hi> Seeds, drawn from thoſe Seeds by Diſtillation. 'Tis very hot in taſt, ſmells ſtrong of the Seeds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Cymini.</head>
                  <p>OYL of <hi>Cumin</hi> Seeds, is drawn as aforeſaid, ſmelling and taſting of the ſaid Seeds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="4 letters">
                        <desc>••••</desc>
                     </gap>amomi.</head>
                  <p>OYL of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>, is the moſt curious and be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ll Oyls, Chymically drawn. The <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> is made in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> of a mo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> fragrant ſmell, yellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh colour, hot and biting, like Fire in the taſt; very heavy and ponderous, ſinking under Water to the very bottom.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Caryophyllorum.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Cloves is likewiſe a very o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doriferous heavy Oyl, prepared as aboveſaid, of a fragrant ſmell, like Cloves,
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:104566:48"/> of a pale reddiſh colour, and ſo heavy, that it runs under Water.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum è Cortice Caryophyllorum.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn from Clove Bark, as the Oyl aforeſaid; but nothing near ſo good, nor odoriferous, nor heavy, as that of Cloves, and of the ſame colour, but a little darker.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Cerae.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl Chymically extracted, by Retort. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Faeniculi Dulcis.</head>
                  <p>OYL of ſweet Fennel-ſeeds, is Chy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mically drawn from ſweet Fennel-ſeeds; of a ſtrong ſmell like it; and in Winter and cold Weather, it will con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denſe like the Oyl of Anniſeeds.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Guajaci.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl Chymically drawn from <hi>Lignum Vitae</hi> Chips, by Retort; of a ſtrong foetid ſmell, of a thick and black Body.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="91" facs="tcp:104566:48"/>
                  <head>Oleum Jaſſemini.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn by Gentlewomen from <hi>Jaſſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min</hi> Flowers, b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ve<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>eration of the Sun; 'tis of a moſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> fragrant ſmell. The beſt comes from <hi>Italy,</hi> and ſome from <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Junip<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS drawn from new Junip<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>erries, by Alembick: The Oyl <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> clear, of a ſweet ſmell, reſembling the Berries.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Latericium.</head>
                  <p>OR <hi>Oleum Philoſophorum,</hi> is drawn from Brick-batts, Chymically by Retort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Laurinum Com.</head>
                  <p>IS made of Bay-leaves, and Sallad-oyl, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Laurinum Fland.</head>
                  <p>IS a green Oyl, very thick and green; made of green Bay-berries, and Bay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leaves. 'Tis brought from <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="92" facs="tcp:104566:49"/>
                  <head>Oleum Macis per expreſs.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Mace, by expreſſion, ſo cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led here in <hi>England;</hi> is nothing elſe but Oyl of Nutmegs by expreſſion; the beſt comes from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies:</hi> In <hi>China</hi> jarrs; of a thick Body, a pale O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>range colour. There is another ſort brought from <hi>Holland</hi> in four ſquare Cakes, but nothing near ſo good as the former.</p>
                  <p>The true Oyl of Mace, by expreſſion, is made in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> out of freſh Mace, and cometh over in Glaſſes and Bottles, being a liquid reddiſh Oyl, ſmel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling very ſtrong of the Mace; (and a little ſowriſh) at the bottom a little thicker than above.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Macis Com.</head>
                  <p>IS a made ſtuff of Sheeps tallow. Palm Oyl, and ſuch like ſtuff coloured, and a little greaſed over with Oyl of Nut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>megs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> is of little value, and leſs vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue than the aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="93" facs="tcp:104566:49"/>
                  <head>Oleum Majorani.</head>
                  <p>OYL of ſweet Marjoram, is of a ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry clear colour, a very little incli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning to a red caſt, fragrant ſmell, drawn by <hi>Alembick,</hi> the Herb being dried firſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Menthae.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Mint, is drawn as the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, of a fragrant ſmell, reſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling the Herb.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Nervinum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>NErve</hi> Oyl, is a made thing here by ſome particular People, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Nucis Moſchatae</head>
                  <p>OYL of Nutmegs, is drawn by Alem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bick, from Nutmegs; is of a clear Oyl, like Water, of a fragrant ſmell, and hot, grave taſt like Nutmegs.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Origani.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn from <hi>Origanum,</hi> by Diſtillati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and ſometimes off wild Time; of
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:104566:50"/> a dark red Colour, of a ſtrong ſcent, a very ſharp and hot-biting taſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Palmae.</head>
                  <p>IS the product of the Palm-Tree in <hi>Guinny,</hi> from whence it is brought, of a red, or rather a deep Orange Colour, of a ſweet ſmell; that which is turned White, and Pale Yellowiſh, is decayed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Petroleum.</head>
                  <p>IS a fat Liquor, flowing from Rocks, and other Stones in <hi>Italy</hi> and <hi>Sicily:</hi> There are two ſorts, the white comes from <hi>Parma,</hi> the red from <hi>Sicily</hi> and <hi>Ita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Roriſmarini.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl drawn from Roſemary, by A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lembick, is very clear like Water, and of a ſweet ſmell like Roſemary.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Scorpionum.</head>
                  <p>IS made with Oyl of Almonds, and live Scorpions put into it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="95" facs="tcp:104566:50"/>
                  <head>Oleum Spicae.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl drawn from Lavender, Roſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mary, and other Herbs in <hi>France,</hi> as they grow together in the Fields, of a ſtrong Smell and clear Colour; it comes from <hi>Marſeilles</hi> in <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Sabinae.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Savine is a Oyl Chymically drawn from the Herb (or rather Shrub) of <hi>Sabina,</hi> by Diſtilling in it in Water by <hi>Alembick,</hi> the Oyl being very clear, ſmelling very ſtrong of the ſaid Herb; the Oyl being often im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported from <hi>Franconia</hi> in <hi>Germany,</hi> wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>re quantities of the ſaid Savine doth grow.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Succini</head>
                  <p>OYL of Amber is Chymically pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pared, by retort out of courſe Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, being rectified 'tis of a light Amber Colour, of a ſtrong ſmell; the firſt draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, is a foetid thick Oyl, of a dark Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="96" facs="tcp:104566:51"/>
                  <head>Ol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>um Sulphuris Com.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Sulphur is Chymically drawn from Brimſtone, of a clear Colour, a clear and acid taſte, and in effect, Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of Vitriol is every whit as good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Sulphuris per Campan.</head>
                  <p>IS Chymically drawn from Brimſtone, the ſame being ſet on fire under a great Glaſs Bell, and gathered in a large Bladder; 'tis of a clear Colour, ſomething inclining to a yellowiſh Colour, of a very acid taſte, and pretty heavy, almoſt with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Saſſafrae.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn from Saſſafraſs-wood, <hi>per A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lembicum;</hi> 'tis of a reddiſh Colour, very hot and heavy, and will ſink under water.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Tart<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ri Com:</head>
                  <p>IS a mixt Oyl of Ol. Tartari, <hi>per</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liquium and Water.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="97" facs="tcp:104566:51"/>
                  <head>Oleum Tartari.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl made of calcined Tartar, hung in an Hipocratical Sleeve, in a Celler which runs out <hi>per</hi> deliquium, in a heavy but clear Liquor, ſome-what ſharp and hot in taſte.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Thymi.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Tyme is drawn from that Herb <hi>per</hi> Alembicum; of a yellowiſh clear Colour, fragrant ſmell and hot taſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>ebinthinae.</head>
                  <p>OYL of Turpentine is drawn out of common Turpentine, which comes out of <hi>France;</hi> 'tis of a clear Body, very hot, penetrating, and of a ſtrong ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Vitrioli.</head>
                  <p>IS an Oyl drawn from calcined Cop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peras, by a ſtrong Reverberatory Fire, when it is rectified 'tis very clear, of a very heavy Oleaginous Body, very hot,
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:104566:52"/> burning a Pack-Thread to pieces in an inſtant.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Oleum Myrrhae.</head>
                  <p>IS Chymically drawn out of Myrrhae <hi>per</hi> Retort; 'tis very thick, and of a ſtrong ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Opium.</head>
                  <p>IS made out of Poppies, being a J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ice boyled up to a Condenſity, ſme<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                        <desc>•••</desc>
                     </gap>ng very ſtrong, of a good lively Colour, cutting eaſily, not hard, being wrapped up in Leaves; the beſt cometh from <hi>Alep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>po,</hi> and <hi>Smyrna</hi> in <hi>Turky;</hi> 'tis brought from <hi>Surrat</hi> and <hi>Perſia,</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt-Indi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>s;</hi> but is far inferiour in quality, being nothing near ſo clean, nor of ſo ſtrong a ſmell, as the <hi>Turky</hi> ſort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Opobalſamum.</head>
                  <p>SEE Balſam Judaicum, Balſam Gilead, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> being nothing elſe.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="99" facs="tcp:104566:52"/>
                  <head>Os Sepiae.</head>
                  <p>CUttle-bones, is called by the <hi>Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans,</hi> the Scum of the Seas, being in effect, nothing elſe but a White Scum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my Subſtance, and theſe are found here in <hi>England</hi> in <hi>Suſſex,</hi> and near the Iſle of <hi>Wight,</hi> and other parts on the Sea<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>ſhoar, thoſe which are large, long, broad, and well dryed, are beſt, they are much ſold by theſe Ironmongers, which ſell Tools to Silver-Smiths and Gold-Smiths.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Os de Corde Cervi.</head>
                  <p>THE Bone out of the Heart of a Stag, is a Bone found in the Hearts of Stags, almoſt reſembling a Croſs, but ſome more than others, being a little flat bone, and to be had in any part of <hi>Europe,</hi> eſpecially, if they uſe thoſe of an Ox in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of it.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="p" type="part">
               <pb n="100" facs="tcp:104566:53"/>
               <head>P.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Piper Album.</head>
                  <p>WHite Pepper, is made from the largeſt black Pepper, by art; being very full, round, large and white. Some has been made here in <hi>England,</hi> but not ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Piper Guineae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GUinea</hi> Pepper, is improperly ſo cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, not any coming from thence, but from <hi>Marſeilles:</hi> That which is in lively red Cods, not broken, and freſh, is to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Piper longum.</head>
                  <p>LOng Pepper, cometh to us from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies:</hi> The larger, and white within, bright without, is the beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="101" facs="tcp:104566:53"/>
                  <head>Piper Nigrum.</head>
                  <p>BLack Pepper, is more of uſe to <hi>Gro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers</hi> and <hi>Druggiſts.</hi> The beſt and largeſt, is your <hi>Malabar</hi> Pepper, being heavy, and of a good ſubſtance.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pix Burgundica.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>BUrgundy</hi> Pitch, comes from a certain kind of Firr-tree, near <hi>Strasbourgh:</hi> That which is ſoft, and of a bright co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, is beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pix Liquida.</head>
                  <p>SOft Pitch, is a made thing by the Shoo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>makers, and of little uſe amongſt the <hi>Druggiſts.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pix Navalis.</head>
                  <p>IS a ſoftiſh Pitch, which cometh from <hi>Godenburgh,</hi> and other places of <hi>Swee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den;</hi> having its name (Ship-Pitch) be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe great quantities are uſed in build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Ships.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="102" facs="tcp:104566:54"/>
                  <head>Pix Sicca.</head>
                  <p>IS the very ſame as Ship Pitch, as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, being only boyled to a dry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs or hardneſs; and therefore called dry Pitch, becauſe the other is liquid and running.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Plumbum Album.</head>
                  <p>SEE <hi>Ceruſſa,</hi> both being one and the ſame; except ſome that are paper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed over, others are not; which go by the Name of white Lead.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Plumbum Nigrum.</head>
                  <p>THE beſt black Lead is found here in <hi>England,</hi> in black Lead Mines; ſoft, and of a firm body, not rocky, ſmooth, in pieces of ſeveral bigneſs. There comes a ſort from <hi>Spain,</hi> and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though it be ſoft, yet 'tis ſubject to be brit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle, and break in ſmall pieces, and Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, that nothing can be made out of it. Another ſort coming from the <hi>Weſt-Ind<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>es,</hi> is courſer and rocky, of little uſe and value.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="103" facs="tcp:104566:54"/>
                  <head>Plumbum Rubrum.</head>
                  <p>RED Lead is made here in <hi>England,</hi> in <hi>Darbyſhire,</hi> in great quantities; and from thence Tranſported to moſt parts of <hi>Europe;</hi> being of a red colour, the next to Vermilion, of a heavy body.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Plumbum Uſtum.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation (which is called <hi>Caementatoria)</hi> of Lead, which is made with Powder of Brimſtone, and the Scales of Lead, which being thus burned, is often waſhed; and thus be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes the <hi>Plumbum Uſtum,</hi> which is uſed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Polium Montanum.</head>
                  <p>IS an Herb which groweth in <hi>Sicily, Italy,</hi> and <hi>Spain,</hi> being covered over with a downe of a lively freſh ſmell, and greeniſh Colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pompholyx,</head>
                  <p>OR <hi>Nihil Album,</hi> having its name from its fine and pure white Colour; 'tis ſaid to be gathered of a Fume which
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:104566:55"/> riſes from Metal (in the fuſion of it) being white and fine, but nothing near ſo heavyas white Lead. It is brought out of <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Priapus Cervi.</head>
                  <p>IS the Piſle of a Hart or Stag dry'dup, of a reddiſh brown Colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Priapus Equi Marini.</head>
                  <p>A Sea-horſe Piſle is of a bony ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance like Ivory, ſome above half a yard in length, thick at the fore part (or <hi>Glans)</hi> and running ſmaller at the hind part. They are brought from <hi>Green<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Weſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Priapus Tauri.</head>
                  <p>'TIS the Piſle of a Bull, almoſt a yard long, dryed up in the Sun.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Priapus Turturis Marini.</head>
                  <p>'TIS the Piſle of a Sea Turtel, dry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed up, is a quarter of a yard long.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="105" facs="tcp:104566:55"/>
                  <head>Pulmo Vulpis.</head>
                  <p>'TIS the Lungs of a Fox dryed, of a ſtrong ſmell; the neweſt, freſheſt and ſoundeſt are to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pulvis Curcumae.</head>
                  <p>POwder of Turmerick is ground in a Mill, of a fine lively reddiſh Orange Colour; being free from all other mix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, ſmelling ſtrong of <hi>Cucurma.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pulvis Enulae Campan.</head>
                  <p>ELecampane Powder, is ground as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, the Roots being well dryed firſt; of a good ſmell, reſembling Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>campane.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Pulvis Glycyrrhizae.</head>
                  <p>LIquoriſh Powder, is grounded out of Spaniſh Liquoriſh, of a pale yellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh Colour, and a ſtrong taſte of the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quoriſh, 'tis adulterated with Flower, whichmay be diſtinguiſhed in the taſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="106" facs="tcp:104566:56"/>
                  <head>Pulvis Santali Rubri.</head>
                  <p>POwder of red <hi>Sanders,</hi> is ground by a Mill, of a fine lively red colour. 'Tis uſed therefore, more in Dying than Phyſical Uſes.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="r" type="part">
               <head>R.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Acori.</head>
                  <p>OF which the trueſt is reckoned to be the <hi>Calamus Aromaticus;</hi> but a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt us here in <hi>England</hi> it is a Root which comes from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> much reſembling <hi>Galanga major,</hi> being larger, more dark of colour without, and whi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter within; not ſo Aromatick, or fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant in taſt, as <hi>Galanga minor.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Alcannae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALkanet</hi> Root, is of a dark red co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour, and white within; that which is ſo the moſt part red, very thin, and not woody, is beſt eſteemed. They
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:104566:56"/> are brought out of <hi>France, Italy,</hi> and ſome out of <hi>Holland.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Angelicae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ANgelica</hi> Root, is a longiſh Root, a large thick Head; a great many ſmall Roots (or large and long Vipers) of above half a foot in length, of a good odoriferous ſmell, a hot Aromatick taſt; the Root is flexible (if new) breaks white within. They are ſometimes mixt with <hi>Meum</hi> Roots, which break of a brown yellowiſh within. They come from <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Ariſtolochiae Long.</head>
                  <p>LOng <hi>Ariſtolochia</hi> Roots come to us out of <hi>France</hi> by the way of <hi>Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcilles;</hi> being a long thickiſh Root, cuts white, a little inclining to a yellowiſh colour within. Thoſe which are freſh, are to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Ariſtolochiae Rotundae.</head>
                  <p>ROund <hi>Ariſtolochia</hi> Roots, are of a round ſhape, much like the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:104566:57"/> Roots; coming likewiſe the ſame way, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Aſari.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ASarum</hi> Root, is a ſmall (Aſh-co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loured) Root, long fibers; of a pretty ſmell, and aromatick and hot taſt. They are likewiſe brought from <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Behen Albi.</head>
                  <p>IS a longiſh whitiſh Root, not unlike to wild Parſnips, but thinner. It grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth in <hi>Italy, Germany,</hi> and <hi>France,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Behen Rubri.</head>
                  <p>IS a dark reddiſh, brown coloured Root; in round rowles or ſlices, like Jallop: It grows as above.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Biſtortae.</head>
                  <p>SO called from its crooked bending to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether; it is likewiſe called the larger Snake Weed, of a whitiſh colour when ſcraped: It grows here in <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Germany, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="109" facs="tcp:104566:57"/>
                  <head>Radix Calami Aromatici.</head>
                  <p>'TIs a ſweet ſcented Root, fragrant, hot, and ſomewhat bitteriſh in taſt; it breaks white, and is a little knot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty as it were. It is brought in Quantities from <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Chinae Optimae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CHina</hi> Roots, the beſt being large, well fed, and firm; cut white and bright within, and light brown without; free from Worms. They come from <hi>Rantam</hi> and <hi>China,</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Chinae Nodoſae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>FLinty <hi>China</hi> Roots are heavy, and not eaſily to be broken or cut, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe of a reſiny flinty Subſtance, which is black, like that of reſiny Jallop.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Contrayervae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>COntrayerva</hi> Roots are of a lively yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowiſh colour, inclining to red; of an inch long, or more, full of little ſmall Vipers round about them; of a good plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:104566:58"/> ſmell, and white within. They come from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Coſti Amari.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IN the Apothecaries Shops, there is ſweet and bitter <hi>Coſtus,</hi> being both of one Species; the neweſt being ſweet, and with Age grow bitter. That which is to be choſen, ought to be of an Aſh colour without, and white within, being freſh, of a firm body and well ſcented.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Coſti Dulcis.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>AS what we have ſaid to <hi>Coſtus A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marus,</hi> it is the neweſt and freſheſt of <hi>Coſtus, &amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Curcumae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>TUrmerick, Terra merita,</hi> is a Root which is brought from the <hi>Eaſt Indies.</hi> There are two ſorts; one long, which is pure and fine, called the <hi>Perſian</hi> ſort; breaks not only of a fine yellow, but gives alſo a Tincture like Saffron: The other ſort is ſhorter and rounder, of a yellow green without<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> That which
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:104566:58"/> is firm, of a lively colour in breaking, and looks not black, is the beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Cyperi Longi.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a long, dark, reddiſh Root, full of lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle knots or ſpecks; breaking white within, of a pleaſant <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ell; 'tis uſed in Perfumes, ſweet Powder, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> It grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth here in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Cyperi Rotund.</head>
                  <p>IS a round reddiſh Root, coming from <hi>Turky,</hi> out of <hi>Syria, Italy,</hi> and <hi>Alexan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dria;</hi> 'tis eſteemed better for vertue than the long Cypreſs Roots. That which is well fed, firm, and hard to be broken, of a pleaſant acriminous ſmell, is to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Dictamni Alb.</head>
                  <p>IS a thin whitiſh Root, of a bitter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh and glutenous taſt. The beſt is gathered in Winter, and cometh to us from <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="112" facs="tcp:104566:59"/>
                  <head>Radix Doronici Rom.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>DOronicum,</hi> is (a kind of a Wolf-Bane) a little ſmall knobby Root, firm, light, brown without, and white within. 'Tis brought from <hi>Germany;</hi> it groweth in <hi>Auſtria, Styria</hi> and <hi>Helvetia.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Ellebori Alb.</head>
                  <p>WHite <hi>Hellebore</hi> (or Sneeſe Root) is a round, ſhort, knobby Root. It comes from <hi>Germany;</hi> a little of it be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſcraped in Powder, will cauſe a vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent ſneeſing.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Ellebori Nigri.</head>
                  <p>BLack <hi>Hellebore,</hi> is a ſmall, black, vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perous Root; breaketh (if good) white within. 'Tis brought in bundles from <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Enulae Campanae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ELecampane</hi> Roots, grow here in <hi>England, Germany,</hi> and other parts in <hi>Europe;</hi> of a bitteriſh taſt, and a pale yellowiſh colour, inclining to white.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="113" facs="tcp:104566:59"/>
                  <head>Radix Eryngii.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ERingo</hi> Roots, <hi>Sea-holm,</hi> or <hi>Sea-holly<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </hi> Roots, a great deal of them are brought from <hi>France.</hi> It groweth like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe in <hi>Germany, England,</hi> and other places in <hi>Europe;</hi> 'tis preſerved in Confects, which are very white and delicious.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Galangae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GAlanga Minor,</hi> cometh from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi> 'Tis cut in little pieces, a browniſh red Coat, and pale red wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thin, of a hot aromatick taſt and ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Gentianae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>GEntian</hi> Roots, is of a bitter taſte, a dark yellow colour within; of a large bigneſs, (not ſlit, which is looked upon the worſt) well fed, firm, break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing clear and bright within. It cometh out of <hi>Germany</hi> in great Quantities.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Glycyrrhizae Angl.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ENgliſh</hi> Liquorish, groweth here about this City, and in <hi>Yorkſhire</hi> plenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully;
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:104566:60"/> being good, 'tis large, thick, well fed, cuts bright within, and is of a good length. It groweth in moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Glycyrrhizae Hiſpan.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SPaniſh</hi> Liquoriſh, is brought over to us; being dry, of a bright colour within, and not blackiſh.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Hermodactyli.</head>
                  <p>'TIs a Root of the bigneſs of a Cheſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nut, white without, and within: They are choſen large, heavy, firm, not Worm eaten; being beaten, will reduce into a Powder, like Flower, of a ſweet taſt. They come from <hi>Syria,</hi> and ſome parts of <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Jalappae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>JAllop,</hi> is a Root which cometh from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies,</hi> being cut in ſlices, and dryed; of which are two ſorts, white and black; of which, the black being reſinous, is to be preferred: The larger and the heavier, the better; the white is not ſo good, eſpecially Worm<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaten.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="115" facs="tcp:104566:60"/>
                  <head>Radix Iridis Florent.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>FLorentine Orris,</hi> cometh from <hi>Italy;</hi> the beſt being very white, full, round, of a ſtrong fragrant ſmell, like Violets.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Mechoacannae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MEcoacan</hi> Roots, is a Root which cometh from the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies;</hi> being very white, ſhrinking a little. 'Tis in pieces a great deal larger than Jallop.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Mei Athamant.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MEum</hi> Roots; the beſt groweth in <hi>Germany;</hi> is a ſingle Root, beard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed at the Head, of a fragrant ſmell: Thoſe which are gathered here in <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland,</hi> are full bearded, and the Root not ſo large.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Peoniae Maris.</head>
                  <p>THE greater <hi>Piony,</hi> or the Male <hi>Piony,</hi> is a reddiſh Root, round and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hick, of no great Conſumption to the Druggiſt, being a thing very ſeldom u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed.
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:104566:61"/> They grow in <hi>England,</hi> and moſt parts.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Phu Majoris.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>PHU</hi> the great, cometh from <hi>Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>many;</hi> 'tis by ſome called Garden Valerian: It groweth likewiſe in <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Polypodii Querc.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>POlypody,</hi> is called by ſome, many Feet, or Fern; that of the Oak (being an Excreſcence) is the beſt. 'Tis found in <hi>England, Germany, &amp;c.</hi> That which breaks green within, and dark coloured without, is beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Pyrethri.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>PEllitory</hi> of <hi>Spain,</hi> is a very hot Root, breaks whitiſh within: That which comes from <hi>Italy</hi> and the <hi>Straits,</hi> is thick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er and ſhorter than that which cometh out of <hi>Germany,</hi> where it is called Tooth-Root.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="117" facs="tcp:104566:61"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Rhabarbari.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THE beſt of all Rubarbs is brought to us from <hi>Turky;</hi> ('tis ſaid to grow in <hi>Tartary)</hi> of fine midling pieces, ſmooth, and not cruſty, freſh coloured, a lively ſtrong ſmell, cutting firm; (in chawing ſomewhat bitteriſh, and aſtringent in taſt) of a freſh yellowiſh colour, a fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant Flavour; not too heavy, nor cruſty, nor hollow, or rotten within. The <hi>Ruſſia</hi> Rubarb is the next to it, which is generally large and heavy, and more cruſty; though ſometimes very freſh, and well ſcented, but nothing near ſo fine as there came lately from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies:</hi> And though it be never ſo good in the Country, yet in the bringing over, it loſeth its ſmell and goodneſs, by the extream Heat of the Sun, turning black and hard within, which is of little va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Rapontici.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>RAponticum</hi> cometh from <hi>Ruſſia,</hi> as al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo from the <hi>Straits;</hi> that which is of a freſh colour, inclining to yellow and red, is the beſt, and the nearer it cometh to Rubarb.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="118" facs="tcp:104566:62"/>
                  <head>Radix Rubiae Tinctorum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>MAdder</hi> Roots are made here in <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland,</hi> at <hi>Wiſbitch,</hi> in the Iſle of <hi>Ely,</hi> and a great deal in <hi>Zealand.</hi> The larg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt and biggeſt, are preferred, being of a good reddiſh colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Radix Sarſaparillae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SArſaparilla,</hi> is brought to us from the the <hi>Spaniſh Weſt-Indies,</hi> is more like long Weed than a Root; if good, very round, well fed, full, mealy, and white within, (if cut) the hungry, and lean, is nothing near ſo good. There is a wild <hi>Sarſaparilla</hi> which cometh from <hi>Jam<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>,</hi> which is large, but not mealy, rather woody and ſtalky; it is worth little to the former. They come in round Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars and long Bundles, and are (I mean the beſt in Collars) brought to us from <hi>Spain.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Serpentariae Virg.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>VIrginy</hi> Snack Root, is a ſmall vipe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous Root, of a ſtrong, hot, aro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>matical taſt, of a Parſnip colour: 'Tis
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:104566:62"/> brought from <hi>Virginia;</hi> the goodneſs is known by the ſmell and cleanneſs, being free from Sand or Duſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Sciilae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SQuills,</hi> are a ſort of Sea Onions, of a large and great bigneſs: There are two ſorts, <hi>viz.</hi> red and white: Thoſe which are dry and ſound are to be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred. They grow in <hi>Apulia, Portugal, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ily,</hi> and other places; from whence <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ey are brought to us.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Scorzonerae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SCorcionera</hi> Roots, are brought to us from <hi>Germany:</hi> Thoſe which are large, freſh coloured, a yellowiſh red without, and white within, are beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Thapſiae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>THapſie Turpith,</hi> is much like unto white <hi>Dictamus</hi> Roots, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> like the ſmalleſt Winter Bark, whitiſh; it is of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ittle uſe, and is brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies</hi> and the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="120" facs="tcp:104566:63"/>
                  <head>Radix Tormentillae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>TOrmentill</hi> Roots grow here in <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland, Germany, France,</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Turpethi.</head>
                  <p>OF <hi>Turpith</hi> there are two ſorts; the beſt is that which is brought from <hi>Turky,</hi> called <hi>Turpethum Alexandrinum</hi> and <hi>Arabum,</hi> thoſe being places of its growth, it is large and gummy: That which comes from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing near ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Radix Zedoariae.</head>
                  <p>TWO ſorts are likewiſe of <hi>Zedoaria,</hi> the long and the round, both being of a white colour, ſtrong ſmell and taſt, ſomewhat near reſembling Ginger. It is brought from <hi>Turky,</hi> and like to grow in <hi>Synnea,</hi> and the further parts of the <hi>East-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="121" facs="tcp:104566:63"/>
                  <head>Radix Zinziberis.</head>
                  <p>GInger, of this the white and black; the white is generally the beſt e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteemed; great Quantities come from <hi>Barbadoes</hi> and other parts of the <hi>Weſt-Indies;</hi> and there is likewiſe a great deal in the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> but moſt which is brought from thence, is confited or green Ginger.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Reſina Pinca.</head>
                  <p>THe Roſin of a Pine-tree, is like com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Roſin, of very little uſe.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Reſina Jalapii.</head>
                  <p>ROſin of Jallop is of a Chymical Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paration, the ſame being drawn from a good black roſiny Jallop; its good<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs is known by being clear, tranſparent in a manner.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Reſina Scammonii.</head>
                  <p>ROſin of Scamony is likewiſe drawn from Scamony, in a Chymical way, as the Roſin of Jallop, aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="s" type="part">
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:104566:64"/>
               <head>S.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Abſinthii.</head>
                  <p>SALT of Wormwood is Chimically made of Wormwood, being calcined very dry and white is the beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Artemiſiae.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chimical Salt made of Mug<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>vort, by calcining, filtring, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Ammoniacum.</head>
                  <p>OF which there is two ſorts, the Pot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lid ſort, and the Sugar Loaf ſort; the beſt is clear and white; the former, which comes from <hi>Turkey,</hi> and the latter which comes from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> is the worſt ſort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Chalybis.</head>
                  <p>OR Salt of Steel, is a Chimical Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paration made here in <hi>England,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="123" facs="tcp:104566:64"/>
                  <head>Sal Cardui.</head>
                  <p>IS likewiſe Chimically made of the bleſſed Thiſtle, by burning it to Aſhes, calcining and filtring, and rendring it to a Salt, which has very little of the taſte of <hi>Carduus.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Cochleariae.</head>
                  <p>SAlt of Scurvey graſs is Chimically made, as that of Wormwood, and therefore much like it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Eupatorij.</head>
                  <p>IS likewiſe Chymically made, from the ſaid Herb, as the other Salt aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Gemmae.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ALias Sal Foſſile,</hi> is a Salt which is in ſtony pieces, like pieces of Cryſtal, almoſt tranſparent, breaking in four ſquare pieces; that which is clear and clean is the beſt. It comes from <hi>Dantzick, Italy</hi> and <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="124" facs="tcp:104566:65"/>
                  <head>Sal Geniſtae.</head>
                  <p>IS Chymically made from Broom, as Salt of Wormwood, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> aforeſaid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Nitrum.</head>
                  <p>SAlt Petre, is a ſulphureous Salt drawn out of the Earth; the beſt is that which will eaſily be ſet on Fire, and which is well refined, clear and tranſparant, in lumps and roches: The greateſt part comes from the <hi>Eaſt-India's;</hi> ſome little may be drawn out of Stables, Cellars, and other places.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>
                     <hi>Sal Prunellae,</hi> or <hi>Lapis Prunellae</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS nothing elſe but a refined Salt Peter, melted down and caſt in Cakes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in a Chymical way with Flos Sulphur.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Succini.</head>
                  <p>SAlt of Amber; is a volatile Salt which comes over in the drawing of the Oyl of Amber; the ſaid Salt playing up, and ſticking faſt to the Neck of the Retort,
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:104566:65"/> from whence it is taken and prepared 'tis of an Acid Taſt, and if well refined will be whitiſh.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sal Tartari.</head>
                  <p>SAlt of Tartar, is Chymically made of Argol, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sael Vitrioli.</head>
                  <p>SAlt of Vitriol is Chymically drawn from White Copperas, off the <hi>Caput Mortum</hi> of Vitriol.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Saccharum Saturni.</head>
                  <p>SUgar of Lead is made by a Chymical way from white Lead and Diſtilled Vinegar: The beſt is light whitiſh, in long Flakes:</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Saccharum Cand Alb.</head>
                  <p>WHite Sugar Candy is made by the Sugar Bakers here in <hi>England,</hi> and moſt parts of <hi>Europe;</hi> the cleaneſt and whitiſt is to be prefered.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="126" facs="tcp:104566:66"/>
                  <head>Sanguis Draconis.</head>
                  <p>DRagons Blood is brought from <hi>Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tam</hi> in the <hi>Eaſt-India's:</hi> 'Tis the Juice of a Tree, whoſe Fruit is red like a Cherry; ſome of it is extraordinary fine, which comes in Drops wrapp'd up in Flags; others in round large Rowls, co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered over with Flags; the courſer is in Lumps: the goodneſs is known by its fine red Colour, when ſtruck upon white Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sanguis Hirci.</head>
                  <p>IS the Blood of a Young Goat, dryed up, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Scinci Marini.</head>
                  <p>ARe Creatures with four Legs, a Head and a Tail, like an Eft; they ſwim in Ponds, and feed upon odoriferous Herbs. They are ſent over dryed up and ſalted; thoſe which are large, not bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken, dry and freſh Coloured are the beſt. They come from <hi>Venice.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="127" facs="tcp:104566:66"/>
                  <head>Scorpiones Terreſtres.</head>
                  <p>SCorpions are a kind of a Venomous Worm or Inſect, much reſembling a Cray-Fiſh, with his Tail having a ſharp Sting bended like a Claw. They are ſometimes brought over alive from <hi>Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>many,</hi> otherwiſe they are dryed. The largeſt are beſt, but the live ones are rec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>koned far better.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Serieum Crudum.</head>
                  <p>IS the Bag, or the ſilken Pouches of the Silk-worm, which the Silk-worm ſpins the Silk upon. They are to be had in all places from whence Silk uſes to come; be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing about the bigneſs of a Birds Egg, and ſome bigger.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sevum Cervinum.</head>
                  <p>STags, or Deers Tallow, is made in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland,</hi> and all parts of <hi>Europe;</hi> being very hard and white, of a ſweet ſmell if freſh.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="to_the_reader">
                  <pb n="128" facs="tcp:104566:67"/>
                  <head>Courteous Reader.</head>
                  <p>THE Intent of this Book was chiefly to know the place of Growth of moſt <hi>Drugs,</hi> being thereto deſired by an intire Friend of mine. The Deſcription, and of the quality of every Drug is difficult enough, but would be more in the Seeds; which cannot well be ſhown but by Eye-ſight: Therefore I have only to all thoſe ſeveral Seeds, which come from beyond the Sea, ſet the places from whence they are brought.</p>
                  <list>
                     <item>SEmen Acetoſae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Agni Caſti.</item>
                     <item>Semen Althea.</item>
                     <item>Semen Ammeos.</item>
                     <item>Semen Amomi, <hi>Streights</hi> and <hi>Jamaica.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Anethi.</item>
                     <item>Semen Angelicae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Aniſi.</item>
                     <item>Semen Apij.</item>
                     <item>Semen Aſparagi.</item>
                     <item>Semen Bardanae.</item>
                     <pb n="129" facs="tcp:104566:67"/>
                     <item> Semen Baſilici.</item>
                     <item>Semen Bombacis. <hi>Barbados.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cardamomi, <hi>major. Eaſt-India's.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cardamomi, <hi>minor. Ditto.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cardui.</item>
                     <item>Semen Carthami. <hi>Germany.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Carui. <hi>Norway.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cataputiae. <hi>VVeſt-India's.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cichorii.</item>
                     <item>Semen Citrij, <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Citrulli. <hi>Ditto.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cochleariae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Colocynthidos, <hi>Streights.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Coriandri.</item>
                     <item>Semen Cucumeris, <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cucurbitae, <hi>Ditto.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Cydoniorum.</item>
                     <item>Semen Cymini. <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Dauci <hi>com.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Dauci <hi>cretici Candia.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Dutroa. <hi>Eaſt-India's.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Ebuli.</item>
                     <item>Semen Endiviae</item>
                     <item>Semen Erucae</item>
                     <item>Semen Foeniculi <hi>com.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Foenugreci. <hi>Germany.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Fraxini.</item>
                     <item>Semen Geniſtae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Hyoſcyami.</item>
                     <item>Semen Lactucae.</item>
                     <pb n="130" facs="tcp:104566:68"/>
                     <item> Semen Leviſtici.</item>
                     <item>Semen Limonum. <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Lini.</item>
                     <item>Semen Lupini. <hi>Portugal.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Malvae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Melonum.</item>
                     <item>Semen Milij Solis.</item>
                     <item>Semen Napi Dulcis.</item>
                     <item>Semen Naſturtij.</item>
                     <item>Semen Nigellae Romanae. <hi>Germany.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Oculi Chriſti.</item>
                     <item>Semen Papaveris <hi>alb.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Papaveris <hi>nig. France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Petroſelini. <hi>com.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Petroſelini <hi>Macedon. Venice.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Plantaginis.</item>
                     <item>Semen Poeoniae. <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Peponum.</item>
                     <item>Semen Portulacae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Pſillij. <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Rutae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Santonicum.</item>
                     <item>Semen Saxifragiae.</item>
                     <item>Semen Seſeleos. <hi>France.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Sinapios.</item>
                     <item>Semen Staphydis Agriae. <hi>Straits.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Semen Sumach.</item>
                     <item>Semen Thlaſpios.</item>
                     <item>Semen Urticae.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="131" facs="tcp:104566:68"/>
                  <head>* <hi>Scammonium.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the Juice of the Roots of <hi>Scamony,</hi> which is full of a Milky Juice, which is thickned and made up in old Boots. The beſt of it comes from <hi>Aleppo,</hi> being clean, free from Sand and Droſs, ſhining like Roſin, breaking eaſily, and if touch'd with the Tongue, turning white like Milk.</p>
                  <p>The <hi>Scamony</hi> which comes from <hi>Smyr<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na,</hi> is generally not ſo fine as the <hi>Aleppo,</hi> being heavy, more droſſie, and ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times full of Duſt and Sand.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sperma Coeti.</head>
                  <p>IS ſaid to be the Seed of a Whale: There has been <hi>Sperma Coeti</hi> Whales caught upon the Coaſt of <hi>Ireland,</hi> but more commonly 'tis found in a dead Whales Head near <hi>Bermoodos.</hi> The <hi>Sperma Coeti,</hi> is to be choſen very white, as Snow, in large and great Flakes, not oyly, or diſcoloured, nor of a ſtrong ſmell.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="132" facs="tcp:104566:69"/>
                  <head>Spiritus Salis Ammon.</head>
                  <p>SPirit <hi>Sal-Ammoniack,</hi> is Chymically drawn from the Sal Ammoniack, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which being very clear, like Rock Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter; but of a moſt ſtrong volatil Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit, enough to ſtrike any Man's breath in ſmelling to a Quantity.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spiritus ſalis Com.</head>
                  <p>SPirit of Salt is likewiſe Chymically drawn from Bay Salt, of an Acid taſt: The beſt is heavy, and of an Amber colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spiritus Mellis.</head>
                  <p>THE Spirit of Honey is Chymical<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly drawn from Honey, by Retort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spiritus Vitrioli.</head>
                  <p>IS likewiſe Chymically drawn from Copperas, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="133" facs="tcp:104566:69"/>
                  <head>Spiritus Cornu Cervi.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn from Harts-horn: The Oyl being ſeparated, and the ſpirit rectifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, is as clear as Cryſtal.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spiritus Cochleariae.</head>
                  <p>IS alſo Chymically drawn from Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy-Graſs, and Spirit of Wine; taſting very ſtrong of the Scrvy-Graſs; and as clear as Water.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spiritus Abſinthii.</head>
                  <p>IS drawn Chymically from Wormwood, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spiritus Sulphuris.</head>
                  <p>IS likewiſe drawn from Brimſtone, by Retort.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spica Nardi Indicae.</head>
                  <p>IS a kind of a Root which comes from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies;</hi> of a fragrant, ſtrong ſmell, and as it were hairy: That which is light, long, and ſhort haired, is to be
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:104566:70"/> choſen; of a yellow colour, inclining to a red, of a bitter taſt, ſticking to the Tongue.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Spica Nardi Celticae.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CEltick</hi> Spicknard, is a kind of Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers made up in bundles; the leaves of a bright yellow, ſomewhat reſembling Marigold-flowers, of a ſtrong fragrant ſmell, being free from Sand and Duſt, and full of ſmall Roots.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Spongia.</head>
                  <p>SPunges grow under Water, at the ſide of Rocks; The greateſt part are brought to us from <hi>Smyrna</hi> and <hi>Aleppo,</hi> and other plaees in <hi>Turkey.</hi> Thoſe which are fine feel ſmooth and cloſe, not too full of large Holes: They are ſaid to grow moſt in the <hi>Archipelago.</hi> Thoſe which are large, fine, cloſe and lively coloured, either white or yellow, are to be prefer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sebeſten.</head>
                  <p>IS a Fruit of a Tree much like unto a ſmall Prune, the ſtone within almoſt
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:104566:70"/> four-ſquare, of a black colour; they are to be choſen: Thoſe which are freſh, plump, full of Meat, and moiſt; they are imported from <hi>Italy.</hi> They grow like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe in <hi>Syria</hi> and <hi>Egypt.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Styrax Liquida.</head>
                  <p>LIquid <hi>Styrax,</hi> is a fat liquor, as thick as many Balſam; of a ſtrong and fra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant ſmell, if clear and good, of a whi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſh colour: 'Tis kept in Water becauſe of its clammineſs. The ſame comes from the <hi>Straits.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Succus Acacia.</head>
                  <p>IS the Juice of a Thorny Fruit called <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cacia,</hi> growing in <hi>Egypt;</hi> out of its Seeds the true <hi>Acacia</hi> is made by Expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion; the colour not ſo black, but more inclining to a red, which above all other, is to be preferred in making of <hi>Venice Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle.</hi> The <hi>Acacia</hi> now in uſe, is made of Sloes in <hi>Germany,</hi> and brought over in round Balls, wrapp'd up in Bladders. The goodneſs is known by its ſharp Reſtrin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gency.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="136" facs="tcp:104566:71"/>
                  <head>Succus Liquiritiae Angl.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ENgliſh</hi> Juice of Liquoriſh, is made in round Balls and ſealed; it is general<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly made up with old Prunes, Liquoriſh, and ſuch other Trumperies, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore far inferiour to the <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Juice.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Succus Glycyrrhizae Hiſp.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>SPaniſh</hi> Juice of Liquoriſh, is made by boyling the Juice to a Condenſity, to make it up in Rolls and Cakes, wrapt up in Bay-leaves: The beſt breaks freely and clear, ſhining like Jet, free from be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing burnt to. 'Tis brought out of <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Succus Hypociſtis.</head>
                  <p>IS the Juice of a Plant, being preſſed out when in its Flowers, and dried up in the Sun, and not unlike to Juice of Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quoriſh; being brought from <hi>Italy</hi> and <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Succus Kermes.</head>
                  <p>JUice of <hi>Alkermes,</hi> is made of <hi>Alkermes</hi> Berries, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and brought over from
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:104566:71"/> 
                     <hi>Marſeilles,</hi> being of a bright Scarlet colour, well reliſhed and taſted, of an acid taſt, and a good Body.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Sulphur Vivum.</head>
                  <p>OR live Brimſtone, is nothing elſe but Brimſtone, before Fuſion, of a grayiſh colour, and acid taſt; and not ſo eaſie to take fire, as other Brimſtone, It is brought to us from <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="t" type="part">
               <head>T.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Talcum Com.</head>
                  <p>COmmon <hi>Tale</hi> looks red without, and white within: There is a great deal to be had in <hi>Germany,</hi> and in <hi>Yorkſhire,</hi> here in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Talcum Venetum.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>VEnetian</hi> Talk, is a Stone which ſhines, of ſeveral colours, as it were of Gold, Silver and green; and therefore by ſome called the Star of the Earth; yet it will
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:104566:72"/> come off in Shivers: 'Tis brought to us from <hi>Italy.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Tamarindi.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS the Fruit of a ſmall Shrub in the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> growing like Aſh-keys. The beſt is reckoned to be the red, of a live<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, ſharp, accid taſt; others like the black ſort better; thoſe which are leaſt ſtony and ſtringy, are to be preferred: They come from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Tartarum Album.</head>
                  <p>WHite <hi>Argol,</hi> or Rheniſh <hi>Argol,</hi> the beſt is that which comes from <hi>Heylbron</hi> and <hi>Strasbourg</hi> breaking clear, and free, without Droſs: It is brought out of <hi>Germany.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Tartarum Rubruns.</head>
                  <p>REd <hi>Argol</hi> is very courſe: 'Tis brought to us from <hi>Genoua, Florence,</hi> and ſome parts of <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="117" facs="tcp:104566:72"/>
                  <head>Tartarum Vitriclatum.</head>
                  <p>IS a Chymical Preparation made out of Oyl of <hi>Tartar, per Deliquium,</hi> and Oyl of Vitriol.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Tea.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a ſmall Herb of a Shrub which grows in <hi>China;</hi> the ſame is uſed in moſt Cof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fee-Houſes: The goodneſs conſiſts of a fine green Tenderneſs, excellent fragrant ſmell, like Violet, and to keep a good, clear, and green colour in the Water; being chewed, ſtreaks very green like Graſs; of it are ſeveral ſorts which muſt be diſtinguiſhed by the Eye, taſt and ſmell, above all the leaves, fine, criſp'd, green, inclining to Razor-blew-colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terra Sigillata Alb.</head>
                  <p>IS a thing made out of fine Earth, and ſealed here in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terra Sigi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="4 letters">
                        <desc>••••</desc>
                     </gap>a Rubr.</head>
                  <p>IS likewiſe made here, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>d ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>led; their goodneſs are according to what Earth
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:104566:73"/> is uſed in the making up of them.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terra Lemnia.</head>
                  <p>IS a fattiſh red Earth, coming from <hi>Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ky,</hi> by ſome called <hi>Axungia Solis,</hi> this is a fatter Earth, and darker red, than the fine Bole; the goodneſs of it conſiſts, if thrown into Water, to riſe up in Bub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, if touched by the Tongue, to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>here to it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terra Sigillata V<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ra.</head>
                  <p>USED to be brought out of <hi>Turky,</hi> ſealed with <hi>Turkiſh</hi> Characters; but of late ſeveral Fallacies being diſcovered, there is a Sealed Earth made out of <hi>Terra Lemnia;</hi> and ſome ſealed Earths are brought from <hi>Germany,</hi> growing near <hi>Stri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gonia,</hi> which is by modern Phyſicians beſt eſteemed.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Terra Japonica,</hi> alias <hi>Catechu.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS a dark colour'd Earth, like to courſe Aloes <hi>Socatrina;</hi> if chewed, it diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolves, taſtes adſtringent in the Mouth, and ſweet in the Throat: 'Tis brought from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="119" facs="tcp:104566:73"/>
                  <head>Terra Samia.</head>
                  <p>IS an Earth which comes from <hi>Armenia,</hi> growing near a City called <hi>Samos:</hi> 'Tis adſtringent, and of a yellowiſh co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terebinthina Com.</head>
                  <p>IS brought to us in great Abundance from <hi>France,</hi> from whence the Oyl of <hi>Turpentine</hi> is drawn in Quantities, and lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle Barrels of ſeveral Weights, are made up for the Druggiſts uſe: 'Tis of a thick Body, ſtrong ſmell, and whitiſh colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terebenthina Veneta.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>VEnetian Turpentine,</hi> is of a thin, clear, tranſparent Body, and indifferent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly well ſcented: 'Tis brought from thence, and ſome parts of <hi>Germany,</hi> as <hi>Brechmen,</hi> being brought down from <hi>Salzburgh</hi> and <hi>N<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>rimburgh,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Terebenthina Strasb.</head>
                  <p>IS of a green, and inclining to an Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber colour; very clear, well ſcented,
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:104566:74"/> and brought from <hi>Strasbourgh.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Terebinthina Cypria.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IS brought to us in Gourds; ſomething reſembling <hi>Chio</hi> Turpentine, but that it is generally foul, and full of Droſs, and a thicker body than any other.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>* <hi>Terebinthina è Chio.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>CHio Turpentine,</hi> comes over from <hi>Turkey</hi> in earthen Pots, is very clear and thick, of a yellowiſh colour.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Tincal.</head>
                  <p>IS nothing elſe but an unrefined <hi>Borax,</hi> brought over to us in Tuppers, from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies:</hi> The beſt, is that which is in large greeniſh pieces, free from Mud, (which it is generally peſtered with) as alſo, ſmall Pibble ſtones) and greaſed o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver with ſtinking Oyl, which is ſaid to be Neats-foot Oyl. The drieſt, cleaneſt, and largeſt is therefore to be preferred.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="121" facs="tcp:104566:74"/>
                  <head>Trochiſci de Viperis,</head>
                  <p>'TIs a little round Cake, made and ſealed, with the Mucilage of the Powder of Vipers, and beaten Biskets, and dryed in the Sun. The beſt come from <hi>Venice.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Turneſole.</head>
                  <p>ARE nothing but old Rags, and Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>non dipped in the red juice of Grapes, (others ſay in <hi>Mulberry</hi> juice) and dried up in the Sun: They ſtrike a red colour in White-Wine, or other Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, like Claret. They come to us out of <hi>France.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>THUS.</head>
                  <p>FRankincenſe, is brought to us from <hi>France,</hi> in large pieces; that which is beſt, is in large, dry and white pieces.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="part">
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:104566:75"/>
               <head>V.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Viſcus Quercinus.</head>
                  <p>THE beſt of Miſſeltoes; are found upon large Oaks, almoſt the co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour of the ſame; other Miſſels are found upon Apple Trees, and others; but not ſo good.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Viſcus Aucupum.</head>
                  <p>OR Bird-Lime, is a thing made here in <hi>England,</hi> with which Nut-Oyl being ſtruck over little Rods, is ſo clam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my, that it faſteneth the ſmall Birds to it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Vitriolum Album.</head>
                  <p>VVHite Cop<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>eras comes to us from <hi>Hamborow;</hi> that in large and great Pigs, white, and not yellow nor duſty, is looked upon the beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="123" facs="tcp:104566:75"/>
                  <head>Vi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>riolum Viride.</head>
                  <p>GReen Copperas is made in great quantities here in <hi>England,</hi> from a round Stone which is found in the Iſle of <hi>Wight,</hi> and old-ruſty Iron.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Vitriolum Dantz.</head>
                  <p>IS made in <hi>Pruſſia;</hi> the ſame running more upon Copper: This is looked up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on better than <hi>Engliſh.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Vitriolum Hungariae.</head>
                  <p>THE <hi>Hungarian</hi> Vitriol, is of a blew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iſh green colour: 'Tis ſaid to grow near Silver, Gold and Copper: Several Counterfeits are ſold for it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Vitriolum Roman.</head>
                  <p>ROman Vitriol, is vulgarly ſo called, it is nothing elſe but Cypreſs Vitrio, in cut Stones, very blew like a Sapphire. There is another ſort which comes in Duppers from the <hi>Eaſt Indies,</hi> not inferi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our to the former, but that it generally runs together in lumps, and not looſe, nor in cut Stones.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <pb n="124" facs="tcp:104566:76"/>
                  <head>Ungula Alcis.</head>
                  <p>
                     <hi>ELks</hi> claws, come to us from <hi>Dant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zick.</hi> The beſt are thoſe which are large, full Legs to the upper Knuckle, full Hooff'd, and well Haired.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Unguent Flor. Aurant.</head>
                  <p>ORange Flower Butter is made from the Orange Flower, and if right, with Pomatum. The beſt comes from <hi>Bermoodos;</hi> ſome good comes from <hi>France</hi> and <hi>Genoua.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Uſnea Cranii Humani.</head>
                  <p>THE Moſs of a Scull of any dead <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ody dying violently, and left unbu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried in the Field, we have ſeen it in ſome Sculls brought from <hi>Ireland.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="z" type="part">
               <head>Z.</head>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>
                     <hi>Zibethum,</hi> or <hi>Civet.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>THE beſt of it is reckoned to be made in <hi>England,</hi> though a great deal more
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:104566:76"/> is made in <hi>Holland,</hi> and with Certificates Tranſported into moſt parts of <hi>Europe.</hi> That which is clear, of a fine, lively, whi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſh colour, not mixt with Butter, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> is to be preferred. The <hi>African, Barbados,</hi> and other Civets coming from the <hi>Weſt-Indies,</hi> are next to it: But that blackiſh ſort which comes from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies,</hi> is by none which underſtands any, looked upon as any thing.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Zinziber Condit.</head>
                  <p>GReen Ginger is brought from ſeveral parts into <hi>England,</hi> as from the <hi>Eaſt-Indies, Weſt-Indies,</hi> and of late, a great deal from <hi>Barbados.</hi> That which is clear, large, not ſtringy, is the beſt.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Zylobalſamum.</head>
                  <p>SEE <hi>Lignum Lentiſcinum,</hi> being the ſame.</p>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
                  <pb facs="tcp:104566:77"/>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="list_of_drugs">
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:77"/>
            <head>CATALOGUS Pharmacorum omnium quae apud PHARMACOPOLAS LONDINENSES Venalia Proſtant.</head>
            <list>
               <head>A</head>
               <item>ADianthum Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bum.</item>
               <item>Adianthum Nigrum.</item>
               <item>Adeps Caſtoris</item>
               <item>Adeps Hominis</item>
               <item>Adeps Urſi</item>
               <item>Alumen Commune</item>
               <item>Alumen Plumoſum.</item>
               <item>Alumen Roch</item>
               <item>Agaricus</item>
               <item>Aloe Succotrina</item>
               <item>Aloe Hepatica</item>
               <item>Aloe Barbados</item>
               <item>Ambra Griſea.</item>
               <item>Ambra Nigra</item>
               <item>Amber Liquid</item>
               <item>Amygdala Amara</item>
               <item>Amygdala Dulcis</item>
               <item>Anacardia</item>
               <item>Antimonium Crudum</item>
               <item>Antimonium Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garum</item>
               <item>Antimonium Diaph.</item>
               <item>Antimonii Vitrum</item>
               <item>Antimonii Ceruſſa</item>
               <item>Aqua Fortis</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:78"/>
               <item> Aqua flor Aurant.</item>
               <item>Argentum Vivum</item>
               <item>Aroma Equinum</item>
               <item>Auriculae Judae</item>
               <item>* Auripigmentum</item>
               <item>Aerugo Aeris</item>
               <item>Aes Uſtum</item>
               <item>Arſenicum Album</item>
               <item>Arſenicum Citrinum</item>
               <item>Arſenicum Rubrum.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>B</head>
               <item>BAccae Alkakengi</item>
               <item>* Baccae Coffee</item>
               <item>Baccae Hederae</item>
               <item>Baccae Juniperi</item>
               <item>Baccae Lauri</item>
               <item>Baccae Myrti</item>
               <item>Baccae Kermes</item>
               <item>Balſamum Capivi</item>
               <item>* Balſamum Judai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cum</item>
               <item>* Balſamum Perua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num</item>
               <item>* Balſamum Sul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phuris</item>
               <item>Balſamum Toluta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num</item>
               <item>Bezoarticum Mine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rale</item>
               <item>* Bitumen Judaicum</item>
               <item>* Bolus Armenus</item>
               <item>Bolus Communis</item>
               <item>* Borax</item>
               <item>Butyrum Jeſſamin</item>
               <item>* Bang</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>C</head>
               <item>* CAmphora</item>
               <item>Cantharides</item>
               <item>Cap. Papaver Albi</item>
               <item>Carabe</item>
               <item>* Caryophylli</item>
               <item>* Carpobalſamum</item>
               <item>* Caſſia Fiſtularis</item>
               <item>* Caſtoreum Angl. Nov.</item>
               <item>* Caſtoreum Ruſſiae</item>
               <item>Cera Alba</item>
               <item>Cera Flava</item>
               <item>Ceterach</item>
               <item>Chamaepitys</item>
               <item>Chalybs Crud.</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:78"/>
               <item> Chalybs Praeparat.</item>
               <item>Ceruſſa Veneta</item>
               <item>Cinnabaris Factitia</item>
               <item>Cinnabaris Nativa</item>
               <item>* Cochinilla</item>
               <item>Corallina</item>
               <item>Corrallium Album</item>
               <item>Corallium Rubrum</item>
               <item>Cornu Alcis</item>
               <item>Cornu Cervi</item>
               <item>Cornu Rhinocerotis</item>
               <item>Cornu Unicornu</item>
               <item>Cortex Cappari Rad.</item>
               <item>* Cortex C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſſiae-Lig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neae</item>
               <item>Cortex Cinnamomi</item>
               <item>Cortex Citri</item>
               <item>* Cortex Elaterii</item>
               <item>Cortex Eſulae Rad.</item>
               <item>Cortex Granatorum</item>
               <item>Cowitch</item>
               <item>* Cortex Guajaci</item>
               <item>Cortex Limonum</item>
               <item>* Cortex Peruanus</item>
               <item>* Cortex Saſſafrae Lign.</item>
               <item>Cortex Tamariſci</item>
               <item>* Cortex Winteranus</item>
               <item>Cranium Humanum</item>
               <item>Cremor Tartari</item>
               <item>Crocus Anglicus</item>
               <item>Crocus Hiſpanicus</item>
               <item>Crocus Martis</item>
               <item>Crocus Metallorum</item>
               <item>* Cubebae</item>
               <item>Cuſcuta</item>
               <item>Cryſtallus</item>
               <item>Chelae Cancrorum</item>
               <item>Cicer. Rub.</item>
               <item>* Cicer Alb</item>
               <item>Colocynthis</item>
               <item>* Coculus Indus</item>
               <item>Colophonia.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>D</head>
               <item>DActylus</item>
               <item>Dens Apri</item>
               <item>Dens Equi Marini</item>
               <item>Diapente</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>E</head>
               <item>EBor Ra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ura</item>
               <item>Elixir Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prietatis</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:79"/>
               <item> Epithymum</item>
               <item>Ens Veneris</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>F</head>
               <item>FLores Baulauſt.</item>
               <item>Flores Chamae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meli</item>
               <item>Flores Meliloti</item>
               <item>Flores Origani</item>
               <item>Flores Stoechadis</item>
               <item>Flores Sulphuris</item>
               <item>Folia Betonicae</item>
               <item>* Folia Dictamni Cret.</item>
               <item>Folia Malahathri</item>
               <item>Folia Roſarum Ru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brar.</item>
               <item>Folia Scordii</item>
               <item>* Folia Scnnae Aleppo</item>
               <item>* Folia Sennae Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lexand.</item>
               <item>Folia Soldanellae</item>
               <item>Folia Tuſſilaginis</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>G</head>
               <item>* GAllae</item>
               <item>* Grana Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rad.</item>
               <item>* Gutta Gamba</item>
               <item>* Gum Ammoniacum</item>
               <item>* Gum Animi</item>
               <item>* Gum Arabicum</item>
               <item>* Gum Aſa-faetida</item>
               <item>Gum Ceraſorum</item>
               <item>* Gum Caranna</item>
               <item>* Gum Copal</item>
               <item>* Gum Bdellium</item>
               <item>Gum Benzoin</item>
               <item>* Gum Elemi</item>
               <item>* Gum Guajaci</item>
               <item>* Gum Galbanum</item>
               <item>* Gum Euphorbium</item>
               <item>Gum Hederae</item>
               <item>* Gum Juniperi</item>
               <item>Gum Lacca</item>
               <item>* Gum Labdanum</item>
               <item>* Gum Maſtiche</item>
               <item>* Gum Myrrha</item>
               <item>* Gum Olibanum</item>
               <item>* Gum Opopanax</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:79"/>
               <item>* Gum Sagapenum</item>
               <item>* Gum Sarcocolla</item>
               <item>* Gum Styrax Cal.</item>
               <item>* Gum Senica</item>
               <item>* Gum Tacamahaca</item>
               <item>Gum Tragacanthum</item>
               <item>Gluten Oris</item>
               <item>* Granadillas Peru.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>H.</head>
               <item>HOrdeum Galli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cum</item>
               <item>Herdeum Perlatum</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>I.</head>
               <item>IChthoycolla</item>
               <item>Jujube</item>
               <item>* Juncus Odoratus.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>L.</head>
               <item>LAc Sulphur</item>
               <item>Lapis Amethy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtus</item>
               <item>Lapis Amianthus</item>
               <item>Lapis Armenus</item>
               <item>Lapis Bezoar Occi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentalis</item>
               <item>* Lapis Bezoar Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>entalis</item>
               <item>Lapis Calaminaris</item>
               <item>Lapis Contrayerva</item>
               <item>Lapis Dentalis</item>
               <item>Lapis Gagatis</item>
               <item>* Lapis de Goa</item>
               <item>Lapis Granatus</item>
               <item>Lapis Haematites</item>
               <item>Lapis Hyacinthus</item>
               <item>Lapis Hybernicus</item>
               <item>Lapis Jaſpis</item>
               <item>Lapis Judaicus</item>
               <item>Lapis Lazuli</item>
               <item>Lapis Lyncis</item>
               <item>Lapis Magnetis</item>
               <item>Lapis Manateae</item>
               <item>Lapis Nephriticus</item>
               <item>Lapis Oſteocolla</item>
               <item>Lapis Sapphirus</item>
               <item>Lapis Rubinus</item>
               <item>Lapis Sardus</item>
               <item>Lapis Smaragdus</item>
               <item>Lapis Topaſius</item>
               <item>* Lapis Tutia</item>
               <item>Lapis è felle Bovis</item>
               <item>Lapis Spongiae</item>
               <item>Lapis Aetites</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:80"/>
               <item> Lignum Aloes</item>
               <item>* Lignum Aſpalthum</item>
               <item>* Lignum Guajacum</item>
               <item>Lignum Juniperinum</item>
               <item>Lignum Lentiſcinum</item>
               <item>Lignum Nephriticum</item>
               <item>Lignum Rhodium</item>
               <item>Lignum Santalum Alb.</item>
               <item>Lignum Santalum Citr.</item>
               <item>Lignum Santalum Rubr.</item>
               <item>Lignum Saſſafras.</item>
               <item>Lithargyrus Argenti</item>
               <item>Lithargyrus Auri</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>M.</head>
               <item>MAgiſterium Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rallior</item>
               <item>Magiſterium Perlar.</item>
               <item>* Margaritae Occi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentales</item>
               <item>* Margaritae Orien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tales</item>
               <item>Margaritae Scotiae</item>
               <item>Manna</item>
               <item>Mater Parlarum</item>
               <item>Mandibula Lucii</item>
               <item>Mel Anglicanum</item>
               <item>Mereurius Dulcis</item>
               <item>Mercurius Sublima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tus</item>
               <item>Mercurius Praecipita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tus</item>
               <item>Mercurius Vitae</item>
               <item>* Myrobalani Belle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ricae</item>
               <item>* Myrobalani Chebu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lae</item>
               <item>* Myrobalani Citrinae</item>
               <item>* Myrobalani Emblicae</item>
               <item>* Myrobalani Indae</item>
               <item>* Moſchus</item>
               <item>Mumia.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>N.</head>
               <item>NUcesè Barbados</item>
               <item>* Nuces de Ben.</item>
               <item>* Nuces Cupreſſi</item>
               <item>* Nuces Piſtachiae</item>
               <item>* Nuces Vomicae</item>
               <item>* Nuces Indicae</item>
               <item>Nuclei Pinei</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:80"/>
               <item> Nuces Moſchatae.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>O.</head>
               <item>OCuli Cancrorum</item>
               <item>Oleum Abſinthii</item>
               <item>Oleum Aniſi</item>
               <item>Oleum Amygdal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rum Amar.</item>
               <item>Oleum Amygdalarum Dulc.</item>
               <item>Oleum Aſparis</item>
               <item>Oleum Aurantiarum</item>
               <item>Oleum de Ben</item>
               <item>Oleum Carvi</item>
               <item>Oleuus Cymini</item>
               <item>Oleum Cinnamomi</item>
               <item>Oleum Caryophyllo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum</item>
               <item>Oleum è Cort. Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ryophyllor</item>
               <item>Oleum Cerae</item>
               <item>Ol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>um Faeniculi Dulc.</item>
               <item>Oleum Guajaci</item>
               <item>Oleum Jeſſamin</item>
               <item>Oleum Juniperi</item>
               <item>Oleum Latericium</item>
               <item>Oleum laurinum com.</item>
               <item>Oleum Laurin. Flan.</item>
               <item>Oleum Macis per ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs</item>
               <item>Oleum Macis Com.</item>
               <item>Oleum Majoranae</item>
               <item>Oleum Menthae.</item>
               <item>Ol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>um Nervinum</item>
               <item>Oleum Nucis Moſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chatae</item>
               <item>Ol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>um Origani</item>
               <item>Oleum Palmae</item>
               <item>Oleum Petrolei</item>
               <item>Oleum Ror<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſmarin</item>
               <item>Oleum S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rpionum</item>
               <item>Oleum Spicae</item>
               <item>Oleum Sabinae</item>
               <item>Oleum Succini</item>
               <item>Oleum Sulphuris com.</item>
               <item>Oleum Sulphur per Camp</item>
               <item>Oleum Saſſafrae</item>
               <item>Oleum Tartari Com.</item>
               <item>Oleum Tartari per deliq.</item>
               <item>Oleum Thymi</item>
               <item>Oleum Terebinthinae</item>
               <item>Oleum Vitrioli</item>
               <item>Oleum Myrrhae</item>
               <item>* Op<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>um</item>
               <item>* Opobalſamum</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:81"/>
               <item> Os Sepiae</item>
               <item>Os de Corde Cerv.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>P.</head>
               <item>PIper Album</item>
               <item>Piper Guineae</item>
               <item>Piper Longum</item>
               <item>Piper Nigrum</item>
               <item>Pix Burgundica</item>
               <item>Pix Liquida</item>
               <item>Pix Navalis</item>
               <item>Pix Sicca.</item>
               <item>Plumbum Album</item>
               <item>Plumbum Nigrum</item>
               <item>Plumbum Rubrum</item>
               <item>Polium Montanum</item>
               <item>Pompholyx</item>
               <item>Priapus Cervi</item>
               <item>Priapus Equi Marini</item>
               <item>Priapus Tauri</item>
               <item>Priapus Turturis ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rin</item>
               <item>Pulmo Vulpis</item>
               <item>* Pulvis Curcumae</item>
               <item>Pulvis Enulae Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panae</item>
               <item>Pulvis Glycyrrhizae</item>
               <item>Pulv. Santal. Rubr.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <item>RAdix Acori</item>
               <item>Radix Alcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nae</item>
               <item>Radix Angelicae</item>
               <item>Radix Ariſtolochiae Long.</item>
               <item>Radix Ariſtolochiae Rotundae.</item>
               <item>Radix Aſari</item>
               <item>Radix Behen Alb.</item>
               <item>Radix Behen Rubr.</item>
               <item>Radix Biſtortae</item>
               <item>Radix Calami Aro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mat.</item>
               <item>* Radix Chinae opti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mae</item>
               <item>* Radix Chinae No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doſae</item>
               <item>* Radix Contrayervae</item>
               <item>* Radix Coſti Amari</item>
               <item>* Radix Coſti Dulcis</item>
               <item>* Radix Curcumae</item>
               <item>* Radix Cyperi Long.</item>
               <item>Radix Cyperi Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tund</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:81"/>
               <item> Radix Dictamni Al.</item>
               <item>Radix Doronici Rom.</item>
               <item>Radix Ellebori Alb.</item>
               <item>Radix Ellebori Nigr.</item>
               <item>Radix Enulae Cam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panae</item>
               <item>Radix Eryngii</item>
               <item>* Radix Gallangae</item>
               <item>Radix Gentianae</item>
               <item>Radix Glycyrrhizae Angl.</item>
               <item>Radix Glycyrrhizae Hiſp.</item>
               <item>Radix Hermodactyli</item>
               <item>* Radix Jalapae</item>
               <item>Radix Iridis Florent.</item>
               <item>Radix Mechoacannae</item>
               <item>Radix Mei Athaman</item>
               <item>Radix Poeoniae Maris</item>
               <item>Radix Phy Majoris</item>
               <item>Radix Polypodii querc</item>
               <item>Radix Pyrethri</item>
               <item>* Radix Rhabarbari</item>
               <item>* Radix Rhapontici</item>
               <item>Radix Rubiae Tinct.</item>
               <item>* Radix Sarſaparille</item>
               <item>Radix Serpentariae Virg.</item>
               <item>Radix Scillae</item>
               <item>Radix Scorzonerae</item>
               <item>Radix Tormentillae</item>
               <item>Radix Turpethi</item>
               <item>Radix Zedoariae</item>
               <item>Radix Zinziberis</item>
               <item>Reſma Pinea</item>
               <item>Reſina Jalapii</item>
               <item>Reſina Scammonii</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>S</head>
               <item>SAL Abſinthii</item>
               <item>Sal Arthemiſiae</item>
               <item>Sal Armoniacum</item>
               <item>Sal Chalybis</item>
               <item>Sal Cardui B.</item>
               <item>Sal Cochleariae</item>
               <item>Sal Eupatorii</item>
               <item>Sal Fraxini</item>
               <item>Sal Gemmae</item>
               <item>Sal Geniſtae</item>
               <item>Sal Nitrum</item>
               <item>Sal Prunellae</item>
               <item>Sal Succini</item>
               <item>Sal Tartari</item>
               <item>Sal Vitrioli</item>
               <item>Saccharum Saturni</item>
               <item>Saccarum Cand. Alb.</item>
               <item>Sanguis Draconis</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:82"/>
               <item> Sanguis Hirci</item>
               <item>Scinci Marini</item>
               <item>Scorpiones Terreſtres</item>
               <item>Sericum Crudum</item>
               <item>Semen Cervinum</item>
               <item>Semen Acetoſae</item>
               <item>Semen Agni Caſti</item>
               <item>Semen Althaeae</item>
               <item>Semen Ammeos</item>
               <item>Semen Amemi</item>
               <item>Semen Anethi</item>
               <item>Semen Angelicae</item>
               <item>Semen Aniſi</item>
               <item>Semen A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ii</item>
               <item>Semen Aſparagi</item>
               <item>Semen Bardanae</item>
               <item>Semen Baſilici</item>
               <item>Semen Bombacis.</item>
               <item>* Semen Cardamomi major.</item>
               <item>* Semen Cardamomi minor.</item>
               <item>Semen Cardui</item>
               <item>Semen Carthami</item>
               <item>Semen Carui</item>
               <item>Semen Cataputiae</item>
               <item>Semen Cichorii</item>
               <item>Semen Citrii</item>
               <item>Semen Citrulli</item>
               <item>Semen Cochleariae</item>
               <item>* Semen Colocynthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dos.</item>
               <item>Semen Coriandri</item>
               <item>Semen Cucumeris</item>
               <item>Semen Cucurbitae</item>
               <item>Semen Cydoniorum</item>
               <item>Semen Cymini</item>
               <item>Semen Dauci com.</item>
               <item>* Semen Dauci Cretici</item>
               <item>* Semen Dutroa</item>
               <item>Semen Ebuli</item>
               <item>Semen Endiviae</item>
               <item>Semen Erucae</item>
               <item>Semen Faenicul com.</item>
               <item>Semen Faenicul. dulc.</item>
               <item>Semen Fraxini</item>
               <item>Semen Fenugraeci</item>
               <item>Semen Geniſtae</item>
               <item>Semen Hyoſcyami</item>
               <item>Semen Lactucae</item>
               <item>Semen Leviſtici</item>
               <item>Semen Limonum</item>
               <item>Semen Lini</item>
               <item>Semen Lupini</item>
               <item>Semen Malvae</item>
               <item>Semen Melonum</item>
               <item>Semen Milij Solis</item>
               <item>Semen Napi Dulcis</item>
               <item>Semen Naſturtii</item>
               <item>Semen Nigellae Com.</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:82"/>
               <item>* Semen Oculi Chriſti</item>
               <item>Semen Papaveris Nigr.</item>
               <item>* Semen Petroſelini Com.</item>
               <item>Semen Petroſelini Maeed.</item>
               <item>Semen Plantaginis</item>
               <item>Semen Poeoniae</item>
               <item>Semen Peponum</item>
               <item>Semen Portulacae</item>
               <item>Semen Pſyllii</item>
               <item>Semen Rutae</item>
               <item>Semen Santonicum</item>
               <item>Semen Saxifragiae</item>
               <item>Semen Seſeleos</item>
               <item>Semen Sinapios</item>
               <item>Semen Staphydis Agriae</item>
               <item>Semen Sumach</item>
               <item>Semen Thlaſpios</item>
               <item>* Semen Urticae</item>
               <item>Scammonium</item>
               <item>Sperma Coeti</item>
               <item>Spiritus Sa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> Ammon.</item>
               <item>Spiritus Salis Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mun.</item>
               <item>Spiritus Mellis</item>
               <item>Spiritus Vitrioli</item>
               <item>Spiritus Cornu Cervi</item>
               <item>Spiritus Cochleariae</item>
               <item>Spiritus Abſinthij</item>
               <item>Spiritus Sulphuris</item>
               <item>Spica Nardi Celticae</item>
               <item>* Spica Nardi Indicae</item>
               <item>Spongiae</item>
               <item>Sebeſten</item>
               <item>Styrax Liquida</item>
               <item>Succus Acaciae</item>
               <item>Succus Glycyrrhizae Ang.</item>
               <item>Succus Glycyrrhizae Hiſp.</item>
               <item>Succus Hypocſt.</item>
               <item>Succus Kermes</item>
               <item>Sulphur Vivum</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>T</head>
               <item>TAleum Com.</item>
               <item>Talchum Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>netiae</item>
               <item>* Tamarindi</item>
               <item>Tartarum Album</item>
               <item>Tartarum Rubrum</item>
               <pb facs="tcp:104566:83"/>
               <item>* Tea</item>
               <item>Terra Sigillata Alb.</item>
               <item>Terra Sigillata Rubr.</item>
               <item>Terra Lemnia</item>
               <item>Terra Sigillata Vera</item>
               <item>* Terra Japonica.</item>
               <item>Terra Samia</item>
               <item>Terebinthina Com.</item>
               <item>Terebinthina Veneta</item>
               <item>Terebinthina Strasb.</item>
               <item>* Terebinthina Cypria</item>
               <item>* Terebinthina è Chio</item>
               <item>* Tincal</item>
               <item>Triſchiſci de Vipera</item>
               <item>Turnſole</item>
               <item>Thus.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>V</head>
               <item>VIſcus Quercinus</item>
               <item>Viſcus Aucupum</item>
               <item>Vitriolum Album</item>
               <item>Vitriolum Viride</item>
               <item>Vitriolum Dantz.</item>
               <item>Vitriolum Hungariae</item>
               <item>Vitriolum Roman.</item>
               <item>Ungula Alcis</item>
               <item>Unguentum Flor. Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant.</item>
               <item>Uſnea Cranij Huma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ni</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>Z</head>
               <item>ZIbethum</item>
               <item>Zinziber Condit</item>
               <item>Zylobalſamum</item>
            </list>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:83"/>
            <head>
               <hi>BOOKS Printed for, and Sold by</hi> John Harris, <hi>at the</hi> Harrow <hi>againſt the</hi> Church <hi>in the</hi> Poultrry: <hi>And</hi> Tho. Howkins, <hi>in</hi> George-Yard, <hi>in</hi> Lombard-ſtreet.</head>
            <p>THere is now in the Preſs, and will ſpeedily be Publiſhed, a very Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent and Uſeful Book; being curious <hi>Receipts in Phyſick and Chyrurgery:</hi> By <hi>Van Helmon<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and <hi>Paracelſus,</hi> that famous Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſician and Philoſopher: Wherein is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, the proper Medecines for all Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtempers incident to Men, Women and Children; with Chymical Tinctures, Chymic<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>l Magiſteries, and Phyloſophical Secrets, of excellent Uſe and Concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cernment. Never before Printed.</p>
            <p>A Pleaſant and Compendious Hiſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of the firſt Inventers and Inſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuters of the moſt Famous <hi>Arts, Myſteries, Laws, Cuſtoms</hi> and <hi>Manners</hi> in the whole World. Together with many other Ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rities and Remarkable things, Rarely known, and never before made publick. To which is added, Several Curious In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventions, peculiarly Attributed to <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Engliſh-men.</hi> The whole Work Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phabetically Digeſted, and very helpful to the Readers of Hiſtory. <hi>Price B<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>und One Shilling.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:84"/>
            <p> 
               <hi>GLOR<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> BRITANNIC</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Or, The Boaſt of the <hi>Britiſh S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Containing a True and full Account <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Royal Navy of England,</hi> ſhewing whe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> each Ship was Built, by whom, and when its Length, Breadth, Depth, Draught of Water, Tuns, the number of Men and Guns, both in Peace and War, at Home and Abroad. Together with every Man's Pay, from a Captain to a Cabin-Boy; truly Calculated and Ca<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> up, for a Day, a Week, a Month, and a Ka<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lendar Year, or 13 Months and a Day. Carefully Collected and Digeſted by a True Lover of the <hi>Seam<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n,</hi> and of long Experience in the Practices of the <hi>N<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>y</hi> and <hi>Admiralty. Price One Shilling.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:84" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:85" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:104566:85" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="30" facs="tcp:104566:86"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="31" facs="tcp:104566:86"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="32" facs="tcp:104566:87"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="33" facs="tcp:104566:87"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="34" facs="tcp:104566:88"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="35" facs="tcp:104566:88"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="36" facs="tcp:104566:89"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="37" facs="tcp:104566:89"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="38" facs="tcp:104566:90"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="39" facs="tcp:104566:90"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="40" facs="tcp:104566:91"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="41" facs="tcp:104566:91"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="42" facs="tcp:104566:92"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="43" facs="tcp:104566:92"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="44" facs="tcp:104566:93"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="45" facs="tcp:104566:93"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="46" facs="tcp:104566:94"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="47" facs="tcp:104566:94"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="48" facs="tcp:104566:95"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="49" facs="tcp:104566:95"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="50" facs="tcp:104566:96"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="51" facs="tcp:104566:96"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="52" facs="tcp:104566:97"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="53" facs="tcp:104566:97"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="54" facs="tcp:104566:98"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="55" facs="tcp:104566:98"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="56" facs="tcp:104566:99"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="57" facs="tcp:104566:99"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="58" facs="tcp:104566:100"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="59" facs="tcp:104566:100"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="60" facs="tcp:104566:101"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="61" facs="tcp:104566:101"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="62" facs="tcp:104566:102"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="63" facs="tcp:104566:102"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="64" facs="tcp:104566:103"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb n="65" facs="tcp:104566:103"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
